<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SpiderSoft</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/</link><description>Recent content on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 10:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.spidersoft.com.au/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to upgrade MySQL on old Linux AMI</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/how-to-install-mysql8-on-ami-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/how-to-install-mysql8-on-ami-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have really &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; AMI Linux instances, and I need to go with more recent MySQL versions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clearing up git submodules problems</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/clearing-up-git-submodule-problem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 12:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/clearing-up-git-submodule-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>As some of you noted I moved by blog into
&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a>
. During the build process you have to pull many git repositories to compile full project. Because begging are always hard. For me it&amp;rsquo;s always trial and error I ended up with having many sub-repositories missing. I’m not going to show whole journey how to solve “the issue”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker, GO and CGO application build</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/docker-go-cgo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 06:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/docker-go-cgo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been avoid Docker for a very long time. I started my career as a sysadmin setting up servers running FreeBSD and early versions of Debian on bare-bone servers. As soon as “cloud” came into to the market I switch to AWS, and GCE and have been using them since then. EC2 was my always goto choice to quickly deploy something on the internet. But Docker — from some reason I was avoiding it until this 2 years ago, when I actually started using it. Without to much trust but…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But today history is not about my love &amp;amp; hate relationship with docker, but about trying to deploy Go application and VIPS library. Couple problems appeared during the process and it’s worth mentioning it for future generations because could find much help around my issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to force clean cached DNS records</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/how-to-clean-cached-dns-records/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/how-to-clean-cached-dns-records/</guid><description>Dealing with DNS changes can be annyoying and frustrating. Changes are not visible straight away, you have to wait to see them. Thet are not even. Here you can find links to clear cached records in popular public DNS servers:
Flushing DNS cache Flush Google Public DNS Cache Purge Cloudflare Public DNS Cache Checking results You can check results here:
IntoDNS Refresh OpenDNS Cache DNSSEC Tools DNSViz.</description></item><item><title>Why VIPS and Go it’s not a good match for production environment</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/posts/2020-07-14-vips-and-go-does-not-play-together/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/posts/2020-07-14-vips-and-go-does-not-play-together/</guid><description>I was building simple worker using Go &amp;amp; VIPS o do some kind of magic with images. I chose VIPS because is blazing fast in comparison with other Go image processing libraries. So this is the story about what went wrong.
Because my DEV setup is Apple MacBook Pro with M1 Apple Silicon it’s always tricky to compile something to the proper architecture. Installing VIPS on my machine it’s pretty straight forward:</description></item><item><title>Quickest in-house HTML to PDF solution</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/quickest-in-house-html-to-pdf-solution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 12:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/quickest-in-house-html-to-pdf-solution/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can find some online API’s use free tier to test them, but… you can make it your own. So without any further intruction here is a reciepe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PrestaShop margin size on delivery slips</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/prestashop-margin-size-on-delivery-slips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:02:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/prestashop-margin-size-on-delivery-slips/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently one of my clients contacted me asking if I can make a change. Shrink a little bit huge margins on PDF delivery slips. The task wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy because settings is bit hidden in the files. By modifying templates you can change font size, and amend or remove elements from the printout. Unfortunately you can&amp;rsquo;t actually decrease margin on PDF printout.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fastest way to install Tesseract on EC2</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/fastest-way-to-install-tesseract-on-ec2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 12:03:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/fastest-way-to-install-tesseract-on-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract">Tesseract&lt;/a>
it’s a great library Open Source library to supply free OCR solutions for multiple libraries. You can use it directly from command line, or in your own software using supplied libraries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CURL to GO</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/curl-to-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 06:44:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/curl-to-go/</guid><description>Quite often we are looking for a quick way to make a request in GO, and we have working query tested in CURL. Sometimes it’s problematic to “move” all queries to GO, and build up whole query using client, protocol and so on.
From the author of my beloved Caddy server there is a tool called curl-to-Go which basically does what is says. Just paste your CURL request and GO lang code to implement that.</description></item><item><title>Automated email parser</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/automated-email-parser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 08:43:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/automated-email-parser/</guid><description>It’s a simple mechanic to decompose emails into useful parts, like some markup (to squiz emails directly into internal systems) and create file attachments – and extract inline images.
Flow is pretty simple, but we have couple components.
We need something to “receive” emails. Easiest way is to use Amazon SES or mailgun or… something else. There is a couple SASS solutions for that Next step is to be notified when email arrive, so we don’t have overhead with checking email every couple of minutes We have to “decompose” – decode email from it’s raw format to text, and attachments.</description></item><item><title>FTP server on EC2 Ami Linux instance</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/ftp-server-on-ec2-ami-linux-instance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 11:11:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/ftp-server-on-ec2-ami-linux-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>People say that FTP is dead. But not everyone knows or can use SFTP, SSH whatever to update their website. Sometimes you just need something as simple as good old FTP server on your instance. Let’s do it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Server on AMI Linux 2</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/web-server-on-ami-linux-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 09:46:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/web-server-on-ami-linux-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome in 2019 – it’s time to upgrade out outdated LAMP stack series articles, with new “How To” setup basic web server for our stack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HTML5 Video tag, and webm</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/html5-video-tag-and-webm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:58:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/html5-video-tag-and-webm/</guid><description>In ancient times, when youtube was born, we didn’t have VIDEO tag. We used to have Flash. To play video on the website, we had to convert it to weird Flash video format, leave mp4 for safety and hope that everything will work fine. Later on, when HTML5 became a industry standard, our live become some much easier.
In the theory VIDEO tag solves all out issues. When browser can handle webm (Chrome family) we play webm.</description></item><item><title>PHP returning wrong date</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/php-returning-wrong-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 10:56:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/php-returning-wrong-date/</guid><description>&lt;p>From time to time we are working on small campaigns, where competition starts at given time. Because in Australia we have “so many” timezones, it’s critical to set things correctly according to the time zone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to secure S3 bucket with username and password</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-secure-s3-bucket-with-username-and-password/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 08:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-secure-s3-bucket-with-username-and-password/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you start looking for a solution you will find answers like: use Cloudfront, use lambda, use middleware 3rd party service. And basically you don’t have any other choice. There is no simple solution to your problem. But – as long as you are using
&lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/">Caddy Server&lt;/a>
solution is super easy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Australian postcode to state conversion</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/australian-postcode-to-state-conversion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:59:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/australian-postcode-to-state-conversion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I was working on a project, when I had super boring address form. I figure out that we need to help poor users fill boring forms, so made a little code snippet / function which gets postcode and returns state. Postcode ranges were taken from
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Postcodes_in_Australia">wikipedia&lt;/a>
, so blame them if something isn’t working as expected.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GeoIP extension PHP 7.x + AMI / Redhat / CentOs Linux</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/geoip-extension-php-7-x-ami-redhat-centos-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 09:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/geoip-extension-php-7-x-ami-redhat-centos-linux/</guid><description>Small 2019 update – Please check out this library – github.com/maxmind/MaxMind-DB-Reader-php It’s a straight replacement of PHP module.
GeoIP extensions is quite use-full, but it requires some server – side magic. If you are looking for something simpler, just go with ipstack.com or something similar – GeoIP .
Otherwise:
wget http://pear.php.net/go-pear.phar php go-pear.phar We need geoip-devel libraries:
yum install geoip-devel
And newest (not stable) version of geoip:
sudo ./pecl install geoip-1.</description></item><item><title>How to run cross browser testing cheaply</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-run-cross-browser-testing-cheaply/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 10:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-run-cross-browser-testing-cheaply/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cross browser testing is a standard part of the testing process. No matter what you build – small page, online form or huge service. It’s really important to test it across multiple browsers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4 reasons why you don’t get a new client Today</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/4-reasons-why-you-dont-get-a-new-client-today/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/4-reasons-why-you-dont-get-a-new-client-today/</guid><description>Each day – new company want’s to make a world better place, and trying to sell you awesome service, API, whatever. I’m constantly searching for new interesting and useful services which could make “my” (my clients) live easier. Everyone has a flashy website, “Try now”, “Try now for free”, “Signup for free” – just fill the form, no credit-card required… entry level – no trouble at all. Let’s do it.</description></item><item><title>How to make email work better email2issue</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-make-email-work-better-email2issue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-make-email-work-better-email2issue/</guid><description>&lt;p>The problem:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are using bug tracking system, as most of the software development companies. Creating an issue is quite simple. Open bug tracking system, fill some inputs, upload attachments – done. Issue is created. Sometimes issue is described with multiple attachments (screenshots). Bug tracking system allows us to embed images into description.  All issues come from users in a form of email.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Binary compression still alive – golang binary compression.</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/binary-compression-still-alive-golang-binary-compression/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/binary-compression-still-alive-golang-binary-compression/</guid><description>In the ancient times, when I was coding mostly in Pascal – size did matter. People were using RAR to shave couple kilobytes from archives, and having 2mb executable was better then having 4mb executable file. In that beautiful time we used UPX – I wasn’t aware that this project is still alive, and works nicely with binaries create bo go lang.
Ultimate Packer for eXecutables Copyright (C) 1996 - 2017 UPX 3.</description></item><item><title>Checking JPEG image dimension from partial headers</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/checking-jpeg-image-dimension-from-partial-headers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 07:43:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/checking-jpeg-image-dimension-from-partial-headers/</guid><description>&lt;p>The goal was to read image dimension from image file. Pretty easy task with standard “&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->image&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->” library and DecodeConfig. The tricky part was – file wasn’t completed – I had only beginning of the file . Obviously I tried to decode headers by myself. I didn’t found exact recipe in GO, and found a lot of people looking for correct answer in many languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with AWS CLI</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/getting-started-with-aws-cli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 07:25:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/getting-started-with-aws-cli/</guid><description>&lt;p>AWS has extremely nice UI. But – with the time, you need to do something faster than just clicking via an interface. Sometimes you need to automate something (start/stop instances, make a backup. If you are wondering – there is a perfect time for CLI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Centos PHP 7 LAMP boilerplate</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/centos-php-7-lamp-boilerplate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/centos-php-7-lamp-boilerplate/</guid><description>&lt;p>This time we are going to cook Apache (httpd 2.4), PHP 7.0 as a
&lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/httpd/PHP-FPM">PHP-FPM&lt;/a>
. Instructions are pretty simple. You can just copy and paste command to get working stack in less then 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you can learn from it? How to install Apache 2.4 and PHP 7, how to enable and opcache, and how to install HTTPS on your server, with purchasing SSL certificate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SWAP space on EC2 on separate volume</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/swap-space-on-ec2-on-separate-volume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 04:27:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/swap-space-on-ec2-on-separate-volume/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s an extension of my previous article – how to create
&lt;a href="http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/ec2-instance-and-swap-space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SWAP on EC2 instance.&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, we are going to create separate volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to choose the right technology for your next project</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/how-to-choose-the-right-technology-for-your-next-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 06:41:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/how-to-choose-the-right-technology-for-your-next-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>People quite often asking me about &lt;em>technology stack&lt;/em>, and where to go with next big project. The answer isn’t simple – it depends. Usually, we have couple components which are critical for the whole system. If we are talking about a web-based solution or any API we have to decide about DATABASE, then we have STORAGE, moving on – some BACKEND service language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to show line numbers in nano</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/how-to-show-line-numbers-in-nano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 09:16:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/how-to-show-line-numbers-in-nano/</guid><description>You can just open file with nano -c filename to make it permanent: nano ~/.nanorc and drop there set const save it… and you are done.</description></item><item><title>When you are running out of space on your server</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/when-you-are-running-out-of-space-on-your-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 10:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/when-you-are-running-out-of-space-on-your-server/</guid><description>…in most cases you have 2 options. Because we are living in Cloud and VPS era – it’s not a big deal. You can always bump up your volume and after while you can enjoy bigger more expensive instance with more space. But sometimes you need just a space for a while or… just something for a backup ? You can always use s3cmd , gsutil or another tool. Imagine that you have just regular folder on your drive, with almost unlimited space.</description></item><item><title>DirectAdmin enable PUT and DELETE requests</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/directadmin-enable-put-and-delete-requests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 17:12:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/directadmin-enable-put-and-delete-requests/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I realised that my
&lt;a href="https://www.directadmin.com">DirectAdmin&lt;/a>
hosting doesn’t support PUT and DELETE requests by default. Apparently it’s necessary to make requests to my recent
&lt;a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/">PrestaShop&lt;/a>
API adventures. As usually quick and dirty solution below. All you need to do, just to drop it to custom configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento 2.1 installation issues</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/magento-2-1-installation-issues/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 11:15:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/magento-2-1-installation-issues/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been recently trying to install latest Magento and was experiencing some issues with Magento installer unable to detect PHP version. My message was pretty weird:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Your PHP version is . The required PHP version is&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>also found couple 500 errors in XHR requests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic PickerView in Swift 3</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/dynamic-pickerview-in-swift-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 09:30:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/dynamic-pickerview-in-swift-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quick and easy dynamic picker view in Swift 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>powerDNS with SQLite backend as a slave for BIND</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/powerdns-with-sqlite-backend-as-a-slave-for-bind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 07:01:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/powerdns-with-sqlite-backend-as-a-slave-for-bind/</guid><description>&lt;p>(powerDNS)[https://www.powerdns.com] it’s a great alternative for huge and bulky BIND server. Light footprint, and quick setup made that server as my obvious choice for slave server for primary BIND server. So let’s config begins:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caddy rewrite and CodeIgniter</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/caddy-rewrite-and-codeigniter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:19:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/caddy-rewrite-and-codeigniter/</guid><description> Caddy it’s a new kid in the block in category super light web servers. Personally – I love it. Same love I feel to CodeIgniter . To marge both of them, we need only basic rewrite rule to drop into caddyfile.
api.spidersoft.com.au { root /var/www/html/spidersoft.com.au gzip rewrite { to {path} {path}/ /index.php?/{uri} } fastcgi / /var/run/php-sock php }</description></item><item><title>JSON objects in PHP</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/json-objects-in-php/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:05:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/json-objects-in-php/</guid><description>&lt;p>PHP is easy. You don’t have to know type of variable, before you use it. But sometimes it’s very problematic especially when we are dealing with JSON.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How schedule start and stop EC2 instance on AWS</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-schedule-start-and-stop-ec2-instance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 14:53:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-schedule-start-and-stop-ec2-instance-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Biggest advantage with AWS – EC2 service, is that you are paying for each minute of usage. So – why run instances 24/7 if you need them only for 12 hours par day ? You can just start and stop whenever you need them. Obviously we don’t want to forgot to shutdown our instance, or start when we need it. Here is a simple recipe how to automate whole task&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Send email using mailgun API without any libraries</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/send-email-using-mailgun-api-without-any-libraries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 10:39:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/send-email-using-mailgun-api-without-any-libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mailgun is well known service provider which allows you send emails via their API or just using regular SMTP servers. SMTP protocol is bit slower, but it’s so common that you can use it everywhere. Each modern application allows you define your own SMTP server to send emails. But… we love speed, SMTP from it’s nature it’s bit slower then regular API call.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up caddy server for wordpress</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/setting-up-caddy-server-for-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 09:03:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/setting-up-caddy-server-for-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com">Caddy&lt;/a>
is a another alternative to
&lt;a href="https://httpd.apache.org">Apache&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="http://nginx.org">nginx&lt;/a>
. For me the biggest advantage is that it’s only one binary file to work with. It’s easy to run, setup and just “works”. It’s super modern – handles HTTP2 and automatic HTTPS encryption using let’s encrypt certificates. Obviously it has plenty of other features but we focus only on speed of deployment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How slow is FOUND_ROWS function in MySQL</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-slow-is-found_rows-function-in-mysql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 04:15:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-slow-is-found_rows-function-in-mysql/</guid><description>&lt;p>From many different reasons I was always using 
&lt;a href="http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.7/en/information-functions.html#function_found-rows">SQL_CALC_FOUND_ROWS&lt;/a>
to get total number of records, when i was running limited query. Never especially thought about it, until i had some super performance issues with one of my projects. Obviously after quick profiling and googling  i found
&lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/186588/which-is-fastest-select-sql-calc-found-rows-from-table-or-select-count">people complaining about FOUND_ROWS() low performance&lt;/a>
. I wasn’t aware how big impact it was until i tested.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to handle max_input_vars restriction.</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-to-handle-max_input_vars-restriction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 20:47:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-to-handle-max_input_vars-restriction/</guid><description>&lt;p>From time to time we could breach 
&lt;a href="http://php.net/manual/en/info.configuration.php#ini.max-input-vars">max_input_vars&lt;/a>
restriction. Which basically limittation for server which allows only limited number of input server to reach out server. Usually this number is around 1000. In this short tutorial I will describe, how to easily avoid this problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PHP 7 on AMI Linux (EC2)</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/php-7-on-ami-linux-ec2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 14:34:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/php-7-on-ami-linux-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p>PHP 7.0 its already a while on the market. Let’s install it on EC2 instance.  Here you can find a quick recipe:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Easy deployment from GIT to FTP</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/easy-deployment-from-git-to-ftp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 13:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/easy-deployment-from-git-to-ftp/</guid><description>I’m huge fan of Continuous Integration and all possible automation which can save me any time during development process. I’m using plenty of different tools in my daily work, but there is always place for something new.
Basically each decent IDE has FTP client build in, but sometimes you don’t have access to your IDE but obviously you got your code in GIT repository. If you are using Bitbucket or Github you are lucky – you can use FTPloy .</description></item><item><title>How to install latest golang on EC2</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/how-to-install-latest-golang-on-ec2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 11:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/how-to-install-latest-golang-on-ec2/</guid><description>If you are looking for simple way to upgrade yourt golang installation on EC2, you can experience error like that:
Error: Package: golang-bin-1.5.1-0.el6.x86_64 (epel) Requires: go = 1.5.1-0.el6 Installing: golang-1.4.2-3.19.amzn1.x86_64 (amzn-main) Because on amzn-main repo, there is an older version of golang – on epel, there is a newer. Nothing simplier just disable for a momement amzn-main repo, and install golang compeltly from epel.
sudo yum --disablerepo=amzn-main --enablerepo=epel install golang-bin</description></item><item><title>PhpStorm PHPCodeSniffer and… CodeIgniter style guide</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/phpstorm-phpcodesniffer-and-codeigniter-style-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 01:26:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/phpstorm-phpcodesniffer-and-codeigniter-style-guide/</guid><description>This article is related to my previous one about setting up PHPCodeSniffer with CodeIgniter coding standards.
Installation on Linux boxes is pretty yeasy:
sudo pear channel-update pear.php.net yum install php-pear-PHP-CodeSniffer php-phpunit-phpcpd On Mac OS X you have couple options. Pear or Homebrew:
brew install php-code-sniffer
And following that, on regular boxes CodeSniffer will be here:
/usr/share/pear/PHP/CodeSniffer/Standards
on Mac OS CodeSniffer will be located here:
/usr/lib/php/pear/PHP/CodeSniffer/Standards or… /usr/local/Cellar/php-code-sniffer/1.5.6/CodeSniffer/Standards
CodeIgniter standard can be downloaded from this location https://github.</description></item><item><title>TOTP security tokens and 2-Step Verification</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/totp-security-tokens-and-2-step-verification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 05:37:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/totp-security-tokens-and-2-step-verification/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Time-based One-time Password Algorithm&lt;/strong> (&lt;strong>TOTP&lt;/strong>) is an algorithm that computes a 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-time_password" title="One-time password">one-time password&lt;/a>
 from a 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shared_secret" title="Shared secret">shared secret key&lt;/a>
 and the current time. The most popular implementation of this solution is &lt;strong>Google Authenticator.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This application that implements 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_One-time_Password_Algorithm" title="Time-based One-time Password Algorithm">TOTP&lt;/a>
 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_token#Mobile_device_tokens" title="Security token">security tokens&lt;/a>
. Usually is branded as “
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Two-step_verification" title="Two-step verification">Two-step verification&lt;/a>
{.mw-redirect}” (or 2-Step Verification). Authenticator provides a six- to eight-digit 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-time_password" title="One-time password">one-time password&lt;/a>
 which users must provide in addition to their username and password to log into various services or other sites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alternate date picker</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/alternate-date-picker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 02:11:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/alternate-date-picker/</guid><description>It’s a very simple prototype of alternative approach to date picker. The goal is to provide easiest way to pick date from very wide range of dates (1800-2099).
Written in pure JavaScript – no dependencies.
demo.spidersoft.com.au/dp/</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/resources/links/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 06:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/resources/links/</guid><description>&lt;p>Couple links&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SSH and SFTP tunnels via ProxyCommand</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/ssh-and-sftp-tunnels-via-proxycommand/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:36:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/ssh-and-sftp-tunnels-via-proxycommand/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently on
&lt;a href="http://www.cyberciti.biz/faq/linux-unix-ssh-proxycommand-passing-through-one-host-gateway-server/">CyberCity&lt;/a>
nice article appeared about using middle server to connect to our destination servers. Most of servers have firewalls which  allow connect only from given pool of IP addresses. So tunnelling is very useful as long we are using it in smart way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Google Cloud storage with AWS libraries in GO LANG</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/google-cloud-storage-with-aws-libraries-go-lang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 01:08:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/google-cloud-storage-with-aws-libraries-go-lang/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/overview">Google Cloud storage&lt;/a>
 it’s Google answer to [Amazon S3][1] service. As long one of them is very popular 😉 Second wasn’t so successful amongst developers due to quite complex processes around service. Amazon is super simple, and developer friendly – Google… well not so easy. So the questions – why you may consider using GS instead of well documented, and super easy S3. Not many people realise but Google Cloud Storage is
&lt;a href="http://www.cloudberrylab.com/blog/amazon-s3-azure-and-google-cloud-prices-compare/">actually cheaper&lt;/a>
. The other reason to use Google Storage is having different provider as a backup solution. Anyway – let’s show how easy is to use GS with existing S3 libraries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terms and Conditions</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/terms-and-conditions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:17:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/terms-and-conditions/</guid><description>In contracting our services or using our website you are deemed to have read and agreed to the following terms and conditions: The following terminology applies to these Terms and Conditions, Privacy Statement and Disclaimer Notice and any or all Agreements: “Client”, “You” and “Your” refers to the company/person in contract with CSL OR person accessing this website, using SpiderSoft services and accepting the Company’s terms and conditions. “The Company”, “Ourselves”, “CSL” “We” and “Us”, refers to our Company.</description></item><item><title>Useful libraries for SWIFT beginners</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/useful-libraries-for-swift-beginners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 06:45:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/useful-libraries-for-swift-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently we started working with
&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/swift/">Apple Swift&lt;/a>
language. It’s pretty simple but very power full language. Learning curve is hard – because it’s pretty new language, but from the other hand it’s good – because there is a lot of freshmen questions on StackOverflow and plenty of articles .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because most of the stuff is related with REST communication with APIs core of my software works with JSON objects. In general we are looking also something for HTTP communication, uploading files and so on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Refund Policy</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/refund-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:33:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/refund-policy/</guid><description>1. REFUNDS, DISPUTES AND CANCELLATIONS</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:23:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/privacy-policy/</guid><description>SpiderSoft is dedicated to maintaining the privacy of our customers. Once you have chosen to become a SpiderSoft customer, we assure you that your personal information will be exclusively used to provide you with the services you have purchased.
WHAT WE WILL STORE
1.1 Account Information – when you establish services with SpiderSoft, you will be asked to provide contact and payment information which will be stored in our system for future billing and customer communication requirements.</description></item><item><title>How update Go library</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/how-update-go-library/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 04:49:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/how-update-go-library/</guid><description>Installation of go library is pretty simple: go get github.com/garyburd/redigo/redis
From time to time, you want to get fresh version of it. If you run that command again it will NOT update the library – because it’s already there. To update it you need to use the -u switch:
go get -u github.com/garyburd/redigo/redis</description></item><item><title>VIPS on Amazon Linux AMI</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/vips-on-ami-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 23:58:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/vips-on-ami-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="http://www.vips.ecs.soton.ac.uk/">VIPS&lt;/a>
 s a free image processing system (library) – in comparison  to similar libraries is super fast, and does not neet much memory. Checkout this
&lt;a href="http://www.vips.ecs.soton.ac.uk/index.php?title=Speed_and_Memory_Use">speed memory usage&lt;/a>
. In most cases you can install it by using this handy script:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>curl -s https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lovell/sharp/master/preinstall.sh | sudo bash -&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In some cases you have to install it from source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>XCache vs APC PHP 5.4.x</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/xcache-vs-apc-php-5-4-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 08:13:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/xcache-vs-apc-php-5-4-x/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I decided to run some upgrades on my servers, and go up to PHP 5.5. I’ve been using &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->APC&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> for a while (convenience) – usually is also bundled with all available repositories, or you can just grab it via PECL. Before that I was always with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->XCache&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->. But… as long APC is no lonager maintained (last upgrade 2012) I make a call about going to XCache. Run some benchmarks, and here what we got.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PHPUnit and CodeIgniter 3.0</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/phpunit-and-codeigniter-3-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 22:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/phpunit-and-codeigniter-3-0/</guid><description>Quick tutorial how to setup proper unit testing with PHPUnit and CodeIgniter 3.0.
We need couple elements
CodeIgniter – we are working with version 3.0rc3 PHPUnit – latest one If you don’t have phpunit installed globally, you can go with composer, just add section to your composer.json
{ &amp;quot;require-dev&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;phpunit/phpunit&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;4.1.*&amp;quot; } } and then
composer.phar install
and after while we have
./vendor/bin/phpunit
working phpunit.</description></item><item><title>What about angular alternatives</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/what-about-angular-alternatives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 05:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/what-about-angular-alternatives/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s my third post in “alternatives” series – this time i looked for something nicer then
&lt;a href="https://angularjs.org">Angular&lt;/a>
. Apparently Angular went the same path like all good and slim solutions. It’s getting slower and bigger. With this type of framework we have at least couple of options:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Riot.js – nice React alternative</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/riot-js-nice-react-alternative/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 05:46:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/riot-js-nice-react-alternative/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I’m looking for easier versions of popular libraries. There is a lot of buzz around Facebook
&lt;a href="http://facebook.github.io/react/">React.js&lt;/a>
library, but i found it not especially user / developer friendly – at least at first glitch. Obviously some people says that it’s not so complicated, but… there is something super simple and super light –
&lt;a href="https://muut.com/riotjs/">Riot.js&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>interesting jQuery alternative – laroux.js</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/interesting-jquery-alternative-laroux-js/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 05:45:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/interesting-jquery-alternative-laroux-js/</guid><description>&lt;p>If we are talking about
&lt;a href="http://jquery.com">jQuery&lt;/a>
alternatives there is not much on the market. With age jQuery put a little bit on weight, not mentioning it’s speed. If we are talking about weight and speed we have &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Zepto.js&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and… we can use pure JavaScript which isn’t especially convenient in larger  projects. But definitely it’s much more but… it’s faster.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iOS Device Screen Sizes</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/ios-device-screen-sizes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 05:24:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/ios-device-screen-sizes/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cheat-sheet-with-ios-device-screen-sizes">Cheat sheet with iOS Device Screen Sizes&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Apache and PHP on OS X Yosemite</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/apache-and-php-on-os-x-yosemite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 03:27:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/apache-and-php-on-os-x-yosemite/</guid><description>It’s just a short instructions how to run Apache and PHP on OS X Yosemite.
PHP and Apache are already there – just need to run Apache and enable PHP. Video showing up whole process is available here:
Here you can check out exact changes.
Firsting first – we have to run Apache
sudo apachectl start
Then make some changes in httpd.conf file
sudo nano /etc/apache2/httpd.conf
Find two lines
LoadModule rewrite_module libexec/apache2/mod_rewrite.</description></item><item><title>FFmpeg on AMI Linux and CentOS the easy way</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/ffmpeg-on-ami-linux-and-centos-the-easy-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 02:12:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/ffmpeg-on-ami-linux-and-centos-the-easy-way/</guid><description>FFmpegis a complete, cross-platform solution to record, convert and stream audio and video.
All you need to do is just install one more repository:
http://rpmfusion.org/Configuration Done.
ffmpeg version 0.10.15 Copyright (c) 2000-2014 the FFmpeg developers&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; built on Aug 30 2014 15:49:19 with gcc 4.4.7 20120313 (Red Hat 4.4.7-3)&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Obviously there is no fun with with FFmpeg if you don’t have anything to convert. I needed to crop vertical videos from iPad to square – Vinelike format.</description></item><item><title>unrar on AMU Linux / CentOS boxes</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/unrar-on-amu-linux-centos-boxes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 03:44:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/unrar-on-amu-linux-centos-boxes/</guid><description>From time to time you have to decompress .rar archives on your Linux. It’s pretty easy. Just download proper RPM package from repoforge repository . In my case it was
Done. To extract archive just use
unrar x yourfile.rar</description></item><item><title>PHP 5.4.x on CentOS 6.5</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/php-5-4-x-on-centos-6-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 04:22:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/php-5-4-x-on-centos-6-5/</guid><description>Quick copy and paste list of commands to get PHP 5.4 on CentOS boxes
Enable remi repo
sudo nano /etc/yum.repos.d/remi.repo Update
sudo yum update done…
now you can follow these instructions to install LAMP stack</description></item><item><title>How to test and capture REST API calls</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/how-to-test-test-and-capture-rest-api-calls/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 03:21:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/how-to-test-test-and-capture-rest-api-calls/</guid><description>Just bunch of very useful tools to help us with testing and building REST API.
requestb.in – just bin for your API calls. Very easy to capture and test calls from APPS
www.runscope.com – older brother, or actually mother of requestb.in – full featured serivce to test APIs</description></item><item><title>HHVM on Amazon EC2 in 2 minutes</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/hhvm-on-amazon-ec2-in-2-minutes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 23:18:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/hhvm-on-amazon-ec2-in-2-minutes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Probably you already heard about 
&lt;a href="http://hhvm.com/">HHVM&lt;/a>
. As on their website:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>HHVM is an
&lt;a href="http://github.com/facebook/hhvm">open-source&lt;/a>
virtual machine designed for executing programs written in
&lt;a href="http://hacklang.org/">Hack&lt;/a>
 and
&lt;a href="http://php.net/">PHP&lt;/a>
. HHVM uses a just-in-time (JIT) compilation approach to achieve superior performance while maintaining the development flexibility that PHP provides.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Using simple terms – HHVM allows you run scripts written in PHP but much, much more faster. Obviously you the main purpose of HHVM is to run HACK language, but it works pretty good with PHP itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MongoDB vs MySQL using golang</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/mongodb-vs-mysql-using-golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 04:48:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/mongodb-vs-mysql-using-golang/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m the guy who like to test. Benchmark is my… middle name. You can find dozens articles about speed one or other solution. I mean
&lt;a href="http://www.mongodb.org/">MongoDB&lt;/a>
and
&lt;a href="http://www.mysql.com/">MySQL&lt;/a>
. I tried MongoDB couple times, and each time I wasn’t  moved by it speed. Got project coming in, when I have to deal with large amount of concurrent connection. It’s not very big, but bigger then casual MySQL load.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So… how did I test – very dump way. Got 2 tables, one around 11k records, second one close to 200k record. Not much. Fields were indexed in both MySQL and MongoDB. And then i run benchmarks. First one had string fields, second one numeric.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to manage logs</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/how-to-manage-logs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 10:16:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/how-to-manage-logs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Capturing and storing longs it’s bit painful task. It’s not so bad if you are running one application on one server, but if you go with multiple servers, or just don’t want to “login” to check logs – you have to go with remote logging tools. I know only 2 and didn’t look for more. First of them is tool called &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Sentry&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> second one is &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->LogEntries&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sending emails from commandline</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/sending-emails-from-commandline/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 04:41:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/sending-emails-from-commandline/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pretty easy but annoying task. Especially when you want to send email using specific SMTP server, or from GMAIL using SSL or add some attachment, or send RAW emails. Solution is there –
&lt;a href="https://github.com/muquit/mailsend/">mailsend&lt;/a>
. Extremely simple command line tool for Linux, Mac OS X and even Windows ;). Compile / download binary and you can enjoy freedom of sending emails from command line.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Live code reload in golang</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/live-code-reload-in-golang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 04:46:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/live-code-reload-in-golang/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recompiling
&lt;a href="http://golang.org/">go language&lt;/a>
 code during development is bit annoying task. But there is an package for that. Actually I found at least 3:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PHP, work queues</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/php-work-queues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 04:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/php-work-queues/</guid><description>&lt;p>Biggest pain point in PHP is lack of asynchronous calls. The only reasonable way is to use some kind of “backend” processing and task list to execute. Some people use cron to run given script each n-minutes and execute tasks. But there is a little bit more “professional” approach. 
&lt;a href="http://kr.github.io/beanstalkd/">Beanstalk&lt;/a>
is a simple, fast work queue. Idea is pretty simple – you can just throw tasks into queue and then have background worker which is pulling data from pipe and executes task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Couple ideas: sending emails, processing images, making heavy queries into database. But the best part of it – you don’t have to use PHP for back processing. It could be anything, because protocol us universal and worker and client doesn’t have to be in the same language. So you can schedule task in PHP, and run it in Go. I’m not going to much into details. Just run some examples.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reading unknown JSON object in go language</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/reading-unknown-json-object-in-go-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 07:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/reading-unknown-json-object-in-go-language/</guid><description>&lt;p>Exploring
&lt;a href="http://golang.org/">The Go Language&lt;/a>
is so much fun. Everything is brand new, and different then any other language. This time I’m going to show quick snippet which shows how to read JSON object with unknown structure, and map elements to something like hash table.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CentoOS 7 NFS support</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/centoos-7-nfs-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 06:45:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/centoos-7-nfs-support/</guid><description>CentOS is pretty new, and some default stuff is just missing. Like NFS suport out of the box.
We have to install package called nfs-utils
yum -y install nfs-utils we can mount using standard mount 192.168.1.15:/c/share
mount -a to make it parmament
edit /etc/fstab
192.168.1.15:/c/share /mnt/nfs nfs defaults 0 0</description></item><item><title>Fetch page with proxy using The Go language</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/fetch-page-with-proxy-using-the-go-language/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 06:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/fetch-page-with-proxy-using-the-go-language/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while i’m playing with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->The Go Programming Language&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> – so far I loved it. I figure out that I’ll push some code snippets from time to time.&lt;br>
Today I spend some time creating simple not ever crawler, but website fetcher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idea is very simple – download page, run xpath query on it and spit out results. I was looking for decent xpath library for Go and couldn’t find any. I tried to use &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->xmlpath&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> but it sucks. I couldn’t even run queries like &lt;code>id('product-details')/div[@class='product-price']&amp;quot;&lt;/code> Then I found something nicer – &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Gokogiri&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> – which works pretty nicely, but – couldn’t find any examples except this &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->small article&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only problem with running Gokogiri is that it uses &lt;code>libxml2&lt;/code> which is not a huge problem on Linux based systems, but on Mac OS X you have to install it via &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->homebrew&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;br>
&lt;code>brew install libxml2&lt;/code>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VPN server on EC2 instance</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/vpn-server-on-ec2-instance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 05:44:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/vpn-server-on-ec2-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The easiest way to setup VPN server on Amazon EC2 instance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with go language on Mac OS X</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/getting-started-with-go-language-on-mac-os-x/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 06:42:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/getting-started-with-go-language-on-mac-os-x/</guid><description>&lt;p>Node.js is like space shuttle – very sophisticated, very fast but one simple mistake and… it goes down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So recently i tried
&lt;a href="http://golang.org/">The Go Language&lt;/a>
 which is advertised as&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Go is an open source programming language that makes it easy to build simple, reliable, and efficient software.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Because google is a creator of this langauge documentation sucks. Plenty of random documents of everwhere, no clean how to documentation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phalcon – super simple REST API example</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/phalcon-simple-rest-api-example/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 04:24:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/phalcon-simple-rest-api-example/</guid><description>&lt;p>Throughout this first tutorial, i’ll walk you through the creation of an application with a simple REST API from the ground up. I assume you have
&lt;a href="http://phalconphp.com/en/">Phalcon&lt;/a>
. installed already.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phalcon is a new PHP Framework of my choice</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/phalcon-is-a-new-php-framework-of-my-choice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 07:11:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/phalcon-is-a-new-php-framework-of-my-choice/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m working on multiple PHP based projects. Most of them using
&lt;a href="http://ellislab.com/codeigniter">CodeIgniter&lt;/a>
as a base framework. I mastered it into stage, where has no secrets for me. The problem is that I also know disadvantages of this bit outdated framework. Recently core
&lt;a href="http://ellislab.com/blog/entry/ellislab-seeking-new-owner-for-codeigniter">team announced&lt;/a>
that they are dropping future development so it means that CI is dead. Doesn’t mean that I don’t like it anymore. I just started looking for something new.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like CI because I got control over everything. Modern PHP frameworks trying to solve all problems for you. It’s amazing, but lack of control is what you don’t need in when you developing projects. What do you need it’s this easy flow during development process. Full control over your MVC structure, but also a lot of “help” from framework itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phalcon cheat sheet</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/phalcon-cheat-sheet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 02:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/phalcon-cheat-sheet/</guid><description>Disable view $this-&amp;gt;view-&amp;gt;disable();
Change main view $this-&amp;gt;view-&amp;gt;setMainView('public');
Set headears $this-&amp;gt;response-&amp;gt;setContentType('text/plain')-&amp;gt;sendHeaders();
 Links to documentation Registering Router instance 404 on Micro application $app-&amp;gt;notFound( function () use ($app) { $app-&amp;gt;response-&amp;gt;setStatusCode(404, &amp;quot;Not Found&amp;quot;)-&amp;gt;sendHeaders(); echo 'This is crazy, but this page was not found!'; } );</description></item><item><title>Apache 2.4, PHP 5.4 on EC2 instance</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/apache-2-4-php-5-4-on-ec2-instance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 04:04:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/apache-2-4-php-5-4-on-ec2-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>This tutorial just updated version of my
&lt;a href="http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/apache-php-config-boilerplate/" title="Amazon EC2 – Installing Apache and PHP boilerplate">previous one&lt;/a>
. This time we are going to install newer version of apache (httpd 2.4), PHP 5.4 but as a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->PHP-FPM&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->. Instructions are pretty simple. You can just copy and paste command to get working stack in less then 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you can learn from it? How to install Apache 2.4 and PHP 5.4, how to enable and APC, and how to install HTTPS on your server, with purchasing SSL certificate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Dev libraries – week 21</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/this-week-findings-in-webdev-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:48:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/this-week-findings-in-webdev-21/</guid><description>I’m consuming enormous amount of news each day. These is list of my findings from just only these week.
Envision.js is a library for creating fast, dynamic and interactive HTML5 visualisations.
Apy is a simple client-side library for making rest api ajax calls.
Sitespeed.io is an open source tool that helps you analyse your website speed and performance based on performance best practices and metrics. It collects data from multiple pages on your website, analyze the pages using the rules and output the result as HTML or JUnit XML.</description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter-minify update</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/codeigniter-minify-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/codeigniter-minify-update/</guid><description>Just introduce some new options to my quite popular library CodeIgniter-minify . From now one you can chose CSS compression engine (cssmin || minify), also FORCE rewrite CSS files. Some speed improvements were also made.
Please feel to checkout library on GitGub – CodeIgniter-minify</description></item><item><title>Quote of the day</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/quote-of-the-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 04:35:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/quote-of-the-day/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The easiest way to share files within same network</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/the-easiest-way-to-share-files-within-same-network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 04:51:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/the-easiest-way-to-share-files-within-same-network/</guid><description>Sometimes you are just to lazy to copy files to local storage server. Sending files over email ? To long. What other options you have.
If you are on Mac – AirDrop is an answer but – you have to be on wireless. What if you are using old fashion cable ?
There is a solution for that – web experiment called www.sharedrop.io ShareDrop is a free app that allows you to easily and securely share files directly between devices in the same local network*, without having to upload them to any server first.</description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter img update</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/codeigniter-img-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 03:49:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/codeigniter-img-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s been a while since my library &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->CodeIgniter img&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> was updated. Purpose of this library is pretty clear – to scale images on the fly using CodeIgniter. It’s very useful in all kinds of website and CMS-like projects. All you need to do, is just load library and inside view use it like that&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>$this-&amp;gt;img-&amp;gt;rimg('path/to/image.jpg', array('width' =&amp;gt; 100, 'height' =&amp;gt; 200, 'alt'='my awesome image'));
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>First time when script hits image, will create thumbnail. Next time, website will get already scaled image. If you need change dimensions, just change it within view – don’t worry about recreating images.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>node.js run with root privileges on MacOS on start</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/node-js-run-with-root-privileges-on-macos-on-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 08:37:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/node-js-run-with-root-privileges-on-macos-on-start/</guid><description>&lt;p>How long it’s quite easy to setup init.d services on linux boxes, same task on Max OS machines is pretty hard. Especially if you need to run it with root privileges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shuttle XS35 V2 and CentOs drivers</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/shuttle-xs35-v2-and-centos-drivers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 10:43:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/shuttle-xs35-v2-and-centos-drivers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some time ago I bought extremely quiet Shuttle &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->XS35 V2&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> device to have something “seperate” for my web development work. Right now this awesome fan less device has many purposes. Works as full web dev stack, with Apache, PHP, MySQL, mongoDB, and even Jenkins machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently I realised that this small ugly device got also WiFi cart into it. Because I’m running out of cables and space in my apartment i figure out, that I could move it easily without plugging into it more cables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PHPUnit and PEAR install on MacOS</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/phpunit-and-pear-install-on-macos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:28:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/phpunit-and-pear-install-on-macos/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is a plenty of tutorials how to install PEAR and  PHP, but there is always something “missing” in this configuration. So this time, i’m going to “sing the same song again”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Utilizing multi core for tar+gzip/bzip compression/decompression</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/utilizing-multi-core-for-targzipbzip-compressiondecompression/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 03:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/utilizing-multi-core-for-targzipbzip-compressiondecompression/</guid><description>We have couple options: pigzand pbzip2.
tar -c --use-compress-program=pigz -f my_archive.tar.gz /home/archive The other trick useful trick is that you can exclude some directories or files
tar -zcvf my_archive.tar.gz --exclude='cache' --exclude='.git' /home/archive</description></item><item><title>Top Screen Resolutions</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/top-screen-resolutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 06:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/top-screen-resolutions/</guid><description>Quite often we are asking this simple question. Where we can answer for that ? On this website: gs.</description></item><item><title>My daily struggle</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/fun-with-css/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/fun-with-css/</guid><description>&amp;lt;img loading=&amp;ldquo;lazy&amp;rdquo; alt=&amp;ldquo;Daily struggle&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;ldquo; https://d1e24pw9mnwsl8.cloudfront.net/c/css.gif&amp;#34; width=&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;460&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Free virtual machines with Internet Explorer</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/free-virtual-machines-with-internet-explorer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 05:22:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/free-virtual-machines-with-internet-explorer/</guid><description>BrowserStackis well known service which provides awesome tools to test your website against different browsers and operating systems. It’s very handy when it comes to professional QA testing.
Not everyone knows, that from that place you can also download virtual machines for free. On this page Virtual Machineyou can pull multiple VM images with IE8 / IE 9 and different versions of windows.
 </description></item><item><title>Latest discoveries</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/latest-discoveries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 22:08:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/latest-discoveries/</guid><description>Codeception Modern PHP testing for everyone codeception.comFileAPI FileAPI — a set of javascript tools for working with files. Multiupload, drag’n’drop and chunked file upload. Images: crop, resize and auto orientation by EXIF github.com/mailru/FileAPIRainLoop FREE, MODERN &amp;amp; FAST WEB-BASED EMAIL CLIENT rainloop.netANIMATED CHECKBOXES ANIMATED CHECKBOXES AND RADIO BUTTONS WITH SVG tympanus.net Odometer TRANSITION NUMBERS WITH EASE github.</description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/resources/downloads/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 10:47:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/resources/downloads/</guid><description>ReadyNAS OS 5 (ARM) Some ReadyNAS popular downloads:
Transmission for ReadyNAS – ARM is a cross-platform BitTorrent client that is easy
Transmission is designed for easy, powerful use. We’ve set the defaults to Just Work and it only takes a few clicks to configure advanced features like watch directories, bad peer blocklists, and the web interface.
Download here: transmission_2.82-0.06-ssurba-arm.bin ( www.sergeysurba.com )
PHP 5.</description></item><item><title>Why AWS is better than Rackspace</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m huge fan fan ow &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->AWS&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> services. It just works – don’t need any kind of support, prices are really good. No issues whatsoever. But – of course my nature ask me to check out other options. For example &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Rackspace&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->. So I registered account, filled out my business and credit details. Just to give a small background – got registered business since 2011 in Australia. I filled out my CC details, phone number and so on. Pretty standard process. I logged in, and start playing with their interface (pretty slow, but I shouldn’t complain yet). The best is about to come…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I don’t recommend mailgun…</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-i-dont-recommend-mailgun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 23:26:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-i-dont-recommend-mailgun/</guid><description>Couple months ago I listed services having API for sending and receiving emails . One of them was mailgun– I was using it for a while since… yesterday. My account was locked without any valid reason. Something related with SPAM:
http://documentation.mailgun .com/razor.htmlReference: #rzr01.
Because I know exactly what emails are being sent using my accounts (I keep track of each email coming out from the system) I was really interested how it could happen.</description></item><item><title>How to force jQuery version on WordPress</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-force-jquery-version-on-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 11:35:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-force-jquery-version-on-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another really simple code snippet. This time, we are trying to force particular version of jQuery injecting into WordPress.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Serialize form to object – jQuery</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/serialize-form-to-object-jquery/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 11:35:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/serialize-form-to-object-jquery/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s pretty easy to serialise form using jQuery –&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>$('#formid').serialize();
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>or by&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>$('#formid').serializeArray();
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>But neither of them it’s easy to modify. Really useful snippet – serialise form to object.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A clipboard manager for Mac OS X</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/a-clipboard-manager-for-mac-os-x/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 01:58:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/a-clipboard-manager-for-mac-os-x/</guid><description>&lt;p>Really tiny but useful program. 
&lt;a href="http://www.clipmenu.com/">ClipMenu&lt;/a>
can manage clipboard history. You can record 8 clipboard types, from plain text to image. To paste a recorded item, you just pop up menu by invoking the shortcut key, and select a menu item from the menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is also snippet function – you can also register texts you frequently use, like e-mail addresses, user IDs and so on. You can paste these snippets from the menu, too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to install node.js on AWS AMI Linux instance</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-install-node-js-on-aws-ami-linux-instance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:25:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-install-node-js-on-aws-ami-linux-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s even simpler than more tutorials are saying. After login to instance, just enable EPEL repository&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EC2 Instance and SWAP space</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/ec2-instance-and-swap-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 23:07:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/ec2-instance-and-swap-space/</guid><description>&lt;p>EC2 Instances on Amazon out of the box, does not contain any
&lt;a href="http://www.linux.com/news/software/applications/8208-all-about-linux-swap-space">SWAP space&lt;/a>
. So if you exhaust memory, machine probably stuck. It’s very good practice, to give them at least slow SWAP memory to save instant crashes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Process is quite simple. Let’s check how much free space we have:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>jQuery SEO URL plugin</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/jquery-seo-url-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 13:09:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/jquery-seo-url-plugin/</guid><description>It’s just a landing page for my jQuery SEO URL plugin.
Sources available on github: github.com/slav123/jquery-seo-url Demo it’s available here: demo.spidersoft.com.au</description></item><item><title>Image Maps</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/image-maps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:17:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/image-maps/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Image Maps&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is quite ancient technology (1993!) to create “clickable” areas on images. Sometimes there is just no other way to handle some some images. Recently I found quite useful tool to create them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Send and receive emails via API</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/send-and-receive-emails-via-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 03:39:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/send-and-receive-emails-via-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s coming with experience. On the beginning you always trying to do everything by your self. No frameworks, no libraries – bare bone solutions written from the scratch. Later – you realising than your time is to expensive, and start using some libraries. After another period of time you are getting to the point, that you are willing to use as many existing solutions as it’s possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really typical problem – sending and receiving emails from the apps. Of course – you can send emails using simple
&lt;a href="http://www.php.net/manual/en/function.mail.php" title="PHP mail">mail&lt;/a>
() command or using more sophisticated libraries like
&lt;a href="http://swiftmailer.org/">Swiftmailer&lt;/a>
but… if there is an option to use API, you can chose from couples:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cut and slice Photoshop files really easy</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/cut-and-slice-photoshop-really-easy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 23:34:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/cut-and-slice-photoshop-really-easy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is one if these rare plugins which make my live lot easier. Actually can’t imagine my work without it. 
&lt;a href="http://www.cutandslice.me/">Cut&amp;amp;Slice me&lt;/a>
 is able to export your assets to different devices in seconds. Whole idea is really simple – name objects, or groups in special way. Click one button – and all assets will be exported in proper file names. It’s getting event better – his plugin is able to export all assets in multiple dimensions (retina images). So… if you ever dreamt about perfect tool for you work – this is it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CSS Sprites online tools</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/css-sprites-online-tools/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 10:26:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/css-sprites-online-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sprite_%28computer_graphics%29#Sprites_by_CSS">CSS Sprites&lt;/a>
 it was a very popular technique for a long time. Biggest benefit from it: reduce number of the requestes to the server, and speedup whole website / loading image assets. Working with CSS slides is really painful  Usually you are starting from PSD then you have to decouple them to separate images, then merge them again to one image, and then mark position of each element in the CSS file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Couple useful tools to work with:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook Page TAB mobile redirection problem</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/facebook-page-tab-mobile-redirection-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 08:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/facebook-page-tab-mobile-redirection-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yes… we have ongoing problem with that really simple function. So – what’s happening. Let’s assume that we have really simple Page Tab existing inside out Facebook Page. URL usually looks like that: 
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/spidersoftau/app_334933569956732">http://www.facebook.com/spidersoftau/app_334933569956732&lt;/a>
 – works perfectly on Desktop browser, but if you would like to open this on mobile, you will get nasty error&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amazon EC2 – Installing Apache and PHP boilerplate</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/apache-php-config-boilerplate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 05:22:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/apache-php-config-boilerplate/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this extremly simply tutorial I’m going to show, how you can deploy basic LAMP stack on EC2 instance. Instruction are pretty basic, without extra comments. You can just copy and paste command to get working stack in lest then 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you can learn from it? How to install Apache and PHP, how to enable and run XCache accelerator, and how to run HTTPS on your server, with purchasing SSL certificate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AUSTRALIA WIDE POSTCODE BREAKDOWN</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/australia-wide-postcode-breakdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 23:14:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/australia-wide-postcode-breakdown/</guid><description>&lt;p>Don’t know how accurate it is. I was working on project, where I needed something like that, so… maybe someone else will use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bootstrap modals via JavaScript</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/bootstrap-modals-via-javascript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:58:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/bootstrap-modals-via-javascript/</guid><description>My recent discovery is quite simple, but really usefull. Bootbox.js is a small JavaScript library which allows you to create programmatic dialog boxes using Twitter’s Bootstrap modals, without having to worry about creating, managing or removing any of the required DOM elements or JS event handlers.</description></item><item><title>Exception tracking in real time</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/exception-tracking-in-real-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 01:26:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/exception-tracking-in-real-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everyone knows that Exception tracking, debugging and checking logs is pain in the ass. Especially when our APP works on multiple servers, or we have different environments, languages which are working as a part of big project. Recently I found exceptional tool created by
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com/">Disqus&lt;/a>
team called 
&lt;a href="https://getsentry.com/signup/r_D1MT/">Sentry&lt;/a>
. What is Sentry ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gearman installation on CentOS and AMI Linux</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/gearman-installation-on-centos-and-ami-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 01:53:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/gearman-installation-on-centos-and-ami-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Gearman&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> provides a generic application framework to farm out work to other machines or processes that are better suited to do the work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This solution is truly multiplatform, so we have Client API and Wordkres in multiple languages like Shell, Perl, NodeJS any couple of others (PHP!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Install GeoIP extension on CentOS</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/how-to-install-geoip-extension-on-centos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 02:32:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/how-to-install-geoip-extension-on-centos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Small 2019 update – Please check out this library –
&lt;a href="https://github.com/maxmind/MaxMind-DB-Reader-php">github.com/maxmind/MaxMind-DB-Reader-php&lt;/a>
. It’s a straight replacement of PHP module.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="http://pecl.php.net/package/geoip">GeoIP from PECL&lt;/a>
is powerful extension used to determine geographical locations of IP addresses and domain names. This is useful if you want to set a language or redirection based on location of your visitor. Check out the PHP docs for a full list of
&lt;a href="http://www.php.net/manual/en/ref.geoip.php">GeoIP functions&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter Bootstrap add ons and extensions</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/twitter-bootstrap-add-ons-and-extensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 05:08:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/twitter-bootstrap-add-ons-and-extensions/</guid><description>&lt;p>My collection of &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Twitter Bootstrap&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> addons is growin each day. As at today we have&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bootstrap From Builder&lt;/strong> – really usefool tool for building bootstrap forms. It works based on rag and drop interface,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Time Picker&lt;/strong> – a very cool widget to easily select a time for a text input using your mouse or arrow keys.,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date Picker&lt;/strong>,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Font Awesome&lt;/strong>,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>snippets&lt;/strong> for Bootstrap &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->bootsnipp.com&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/li>
&lt;li>golderBootstrap – &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->phildionne.github.com/golden-bootstrap/#goldenBootstrap&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>BootStrap Notify&lt;/strong> – &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->nijikokun.github.com/bootstrap-notify/&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Pivot.js&lt;/strong> is a simple way to summarize large data sets on the fly,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>PhpStorm 5 Released</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/phpstorm-5-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 05:24:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/phpstorm-5-released/</guid><description>PhpStorm is great PHP IDE for all kind of web development practices. JetBrains just release latest version 5.0. List of changes is quite long, my recommendation is to read what’s new list.</description></item><item><title>Twitter Bootstrap typeahead and ajax</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/twitter-bootstrap-typeahead-and-ajax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 09:16:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/twitter-bootstrap-typeahead-and-ajax/</guid><description> Typeahead is a basic, easily extended plugin for quickly creating elegant typeaheads with any form text input. Working with Twitter Bootstrap. Multiple options, are not explained in details on project website. So… Quick example of usage
$('.typeahead').typeahead({ source: function (query, process) { return $.get('/typeahead', { query: query }, function (data) { return process(data); }); } });</description></item><item><title>AngularJS examples</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/angularjs-examples/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 09:20:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/angularjs-examples/</guid><description>Did I mentioned before that I love AngularJS? No? – I love it.
Whole bunch of examples, but not of them are working:  JSFiddle-Examples -Angular JS examples Shoping cart with Angular JS Infinite scroling AngularJS Simple table sorting Simple proportion calculator Simple search with PHP and AngularJS</description></item><item><title>How to install Phing on CentOS</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/how-to-install-phing-on-centos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 07:45:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/how-to-install-phing-on-centos/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="http://phing.info/trac/">PHing&lt;/a>
 &lt;strong>I&lt;/strong>s &lt;strong>N&lt;/strong>ot &lt;strong>G&lt;/strong>NU make; it’s a PHP project build system or build tool based on 
&lt;a href="http://ant.apache.org/"> Apache Ant&lt;/a>
. You can do anything with it that you could do with a traditional build system like GNU make, and its use of simple XML build files and extensible PHP “task” classes make it an easy-to-use and highly flexible build framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This build tool ensures that the process of creating your  web application from source code happens in a proper and repeatable way. This is the best way to reduce the possibility of errors caused by manual uploads via FTP or SSH using desktop client.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sublime2 favourite configuration</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/sublime2-favourite-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 11:01:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/sublime2-favourite-configuration/</guid><description>&lt;p>As long as I’m not huge fan of
&lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text 2&lt;/a>
– I have to admin it’s really fast. This is the fastest editor which I ever seen. So – for quick edit I’m usually using it. But there are 2 annoying default settings which I really can’t stand: opening each file in new tab, and moving to the end of the file on “end” keystroke. Finally I founded how to solve my daily problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Easy wireframes with Moqups</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/easy-wireframes-with-moqups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 12:50:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/easy-wireframes-with-moqups/</guid><description>Creating wireframes is a very tedious job, but now there is new webapp for that – unfortunately you don’t have to use iPhone to make really easy and quick wireframes. Only think which you need is only HTML5 browser, and a little bit of free time. Check it now: Moqups</description></item><item><title>CentOS 6.2 php-mcrypt and EPEL repo</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/centos-6-2-php-mcrypt-and-epel-repo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 10:28:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/centos-6-2-php-mcrypt-and-epel-repo/</guid><description>You will find plenty of “how-to” tutorials, but usually with not working url to EPEL repo. So this is mine:
yum install http://download.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/6/x86_64/epel-release-6-7.noarch.rpm yum update yum install php-mcrypt</description></item><item><title>AngularJS awesome JavaScript framework</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/angularjs-awesome-javascript-framework/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 11:27:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/angularjs-awesome-javascript-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was looking for easy and nice solution to maintain my growing JavaScript. I tried
&lt;a href="http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/collection-of-backbone-js-tutorials/" title="Collection of Backbone.js tutorials">Backbone.js&lt;/a>
 which is my opinion a little bit “to” complicated. Of course – you can do everything, but.. it was to much hassle with coding in details. Second approach was to
&lt;a href="http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/collection-of-knockout-js-tutorials/" title="Collection of Knockout.js tutorials">KnockoutJS&lt;/a>
 – this one is really nice but from the other hand – I didn’t have much on control on my code and details, but everything was really nice and sleek. So… Quite similar like with choosing PHP Framework. I wanted something which will do some job for me, but I also wanted to have control on everything. That’s why I chose CodeIgniter which was perfect for me. But… with JavaScript – Finally i funded:
&lt;a href="http://angularjs.org/">AngularJS&lt;/a>
. Made by Google engineers – but super nice and sleek.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Most complete Twitter Bootstrap PSD template</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/moste-complete-twitter-bootstrap-psd-template/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 10:11:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/moste-complete-twitter-bootstrap-psd-template/</guid><description>Twitter Bootstrap revolutionised work of backend developer. It’s powerful front-end framework for faster and easier web development. No longer we have to worry about “how to create prototype our apps in fast and efficient way.” But… sometimes we need to move one step back, and create mockup / or wireframes using Twitter Bootstrap elements – how? It’s quite simple – we can use Photoshop Template for Designers by Utah Web Design.</description></item><item><title>Amazon AWS finally in Australia</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</guid><description>Finally we can enjoy power and speed of Amazon AWS services, in Australia but… so far we can’t get full experience, it’s only for two services – Amazon Route 53 and Amazon CloudFront . So… in simple words we can enjoy with 100% SLA DNS service and global CDN with edge location based on Sydney.</description></item><item><title>Amazon RDS for $20 monthly</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-rds-for-20-monthly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 07:52:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-rds-for-20-monthly/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon AWS
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2012/06/11/amazon-rds-micro/">just announced&lt;/a>
that Micro instances can be used for
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/rds/">Amazon RDS&lt;/a>
with MySQL database engine which is really good news. Previously cheapest option  was Small Instance which was quite “expensive” with $0.105 USD for on hour (without reserved instances). Now we can use RDS with MySQL for $0.025 hourly! We can go even lower with reserved instances. Details about pricing are
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/rds/pricing/">available here&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web thumbnails for free</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/web-thumbnails-for-free/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 23:45:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/web-thumbnails-for-free/</guid><description>Taking snapshots of websites – it’s very simple thing, but … you need to install an browser extension – I’m using Awesome Screenshot , or use magic shortcut in Mac OS X. You can also take advantage of services specializing in this task, but as far as I know there are not many free solutions. So today I will describe the project webthumbnail.org .&amp;lt;/
The idea is very simple – generate snapshots of the page at any resolution, we can choose between several browsers (Chrome, FireFox, Opera).</description></item><item><title>Collection of Knockout.js tutorials</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/collection-of-knockout-js-tutorials/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 01:08:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/collection-of-knockout-js-tutorials/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Knockout.js&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is a JavaScript library that helps you to create rich, responsive display and editor user interfaces with a clean underlying data model. Any time you have sections of UI that update dynamically (e.g., changing depending on the user’s actions or when an external data source changes), KO can help you implement it more simply and maintainably.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Collection of Backbone.js tutorials</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/collection-of-backbone-js-tutorials/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:38:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/collection-of-backbone-js-tutorials/</guid><description>&lt;p>Backbone.js gives structure to web applications by providing models with key-value binding and custom events, collections with a rich API of enumerable functions, views with declarative event handling, and connects it all to your existing API over a RESTful JSON interface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mac OS X Window Manager</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/mac-os-x-window-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 08:08:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/mac-os-x-window-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was looking for some kind of easy to use Window Manager for Mac OS X. Usually I’m working on multiple screen with multiple application open (usually it’s between 4-8). It’s really hard to organise everything in proper order and placement. Arranging windows it’s slow, especially when you need to compare or see results on multiple window at once.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter and PHP_CodeSniffer</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/codeigniter-and-php_codesniffer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 08:28:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/codeigniter-and-php_codesniffer/</guid><description>CodeIgniteris the king 😉 But if we want to create good quality code, we should be aware about CodeIgniter style guidestandards. What can be better than PHP_CodeSnifferfor keeping our code consistent and clean as much as it possible.
Unfortunately standard rules from PHP_CodeSniffer doesn’t apply for CodeIgniter. You have to install additional set of rules – you can download them from here: PHP_CodeSniffer rules for CI.</description></item><item><title>JavaScript Lint compilation</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/javascript-lint-compilation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 09:28:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/javascript-lint-compilation/</guid><description>JavaScript Lintallows you to validate JavaScript files from command line. For Windows and Mac OS Boxex we can download precompiled binaries.
I don’t know why authors missed part in documentation which describes how to compile this under Linux box.
Here is missing interaction:
wget http://www.javascriptlint.com/download/jsl-0.3.0-src.tar.gz tar zxvf jsl-0.3.0-src.tar.gz cd jsl-0.3.0/src/ make -f Makefile.ref sudo cp Linux_All_DBG.OBJ/jsl /usr/local/bin</description></item><item><title>iBrowser and TinyMCE</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/ibrowser-and-tinymce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 12:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/ibrowser-and-tinymce/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can find plenty of tutorials how to setup tinyMCE and iBrowser, but non of them mention about common problems, like “error building image list!”, or how to bind regular image browser to iBrowser. Here you can find full instructions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WordPress starter theme – Foundation</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/wordpress-starter-theme-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 18:33:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/wordpress-starter-theme-foundation/</guid><description>Foundationis a rapid prototyping and building library from ZURB. Which is basically great CSS framework. Light, quick in development and good looking. In last days I just discover great based starter theme based on this CSS framework – check it out Foundation for WordPressor just download directly from GitHub</description></item><item><title>Apache Virtual Hosts in a Database</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/apache-virtual-hosts-in-a-database/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/apache-virtual-hosts-in-a-database/</guid><description>&lt;p>As much as I love &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->lighttpd&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> sometimes I can’t avoid &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Apache&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->. For me – “the best” thing in lighttpd is support for keeping vhost names in MySQL database. I don’t have to use any config files, I can just put record into MySQL database with virtual host server name, path to document root and it’s done. But – I can do the same witch Apache! How? With third party modules, belov you can find short tutorial “how to”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter Uploadify problem</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/codeigniter-uploadify-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 02:37:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/codeigniter-uploadify-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>I tried to implement Uploadify with
&lt;a href="http://codeigniter.com/user_guide/libraries/file_uploading.html">CodeIgniter upload class&lt;/a>
, and had some issues with recognising proper mime types.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CentOS 6 and Mac OS Extended (HFS Plus) support</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/centos-6-and-mac-os-extended-hfs-plus-support/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 02:43:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/centos-6-and-mac-os-extended-hfs-plus-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>By default CentOS 6 does not have support for Mac OS Extended
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HFS_Plus">HFS Plus&lt;/a>
support.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>HFS Plus or HFS+ is a file system developed by Apple Inc. to replace their Hierarchical File System (HFS) as the primary file system used in Macintosh computers (or other systems running Mac OS). It is also one of the formats used by the iPod digital music player. HFS Plus is also referred to as Mac OS Extended (or, erroneously, “HFS Extended”), where its predecessor, HFS, is also referred to as Mac OS Standard (or, erroneously, as “HFS Standard”)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>IPv4 Checksum error</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/ipv4-checksum-error/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 00:09:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/ipv4-checksum-error/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my Linux boxes started to reporting unexpected&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>jme 0000:02:00.5: eth1: IPv4 Checksum error&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>on ethernet interface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>XCache driver CodeIgniter update</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/xcache-driver-codeigniter-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 05:47:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/xcache-driver-codeigniter-update/</guid><description>Today I released small update for XCache diver for CodeIgniter . It’s related with new version of CodeIgniter framework.</description></item><item><title>How to get better results with ImageMagick and convert</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-get-better-results-with-imagemagick-and-convert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 23:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-get-better-results-with-imagemagick-and-convert/</guid><description>In last two days I’m trying to find best way to convert PDF files to good quality JPEG files. Of course size does matter, not only in case of women breasts.
When I was trying convert files directly from PDF to JPEG results was pretty scary:
convert myfile.pdf[1] dc.jpg
number 1 in brackets means only one(second) page to process.
As I result I get file with pretty huge size: 496.8K</description></item><item><title>Lighttpd and upload_max_filesize</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-upload_max_filesize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 01:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-upload_max_filesize/</guid><description>Default setting for uploading file size in PHP is really small. Usually it’s about 2MB. To increase this limit, you need to change one obvious variable:
upload_max_filesize = 20M Eventually you can also increase max number of files to upload:
max_file_uploads = 20 But… this is not enough. Because on lighttpd PHP is working as a FastCGI process when you start uploading bigger files, you can get this bad message:</description></item><item><title>Google mod-pagespeed on CentOS</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-mod-pagespeed-on-centos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:48:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-mod-pagespeed-on-centos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Short “How to” install Google mod-pagespeed on CentOs. You can read more about this Apache module on this page: Google &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->mod_pagespeed overview&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->. Basicly it’s a module which gives your website speedup. Many simple techniques to reduce size and number of requests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lighttpd and mod_expire</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-mod_expire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 03:39:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-mod_expire/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Page Speed Online&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is really good service for measuring and optimising your website. After deep analysis we get a lot if clues how to improve speed of your website. But how to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Leverage browser caching&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> if we have &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Lighttpd&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> instead default Apache? We need to use &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->mod_expire&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drupal and lighttpd mod_rewrite settings</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/drupal-and-lighttpd-mod_rewrite-settings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 03:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/drupal-and-lighttpd-mod_rewrite-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lighttpd is awesome and very fast webserver. But has one big disadvantage – is not reading apache .htaccess files with rewrite settings. Unfortunatley you need to create them manually in config file. How? Examples are below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Posftix Permission denied problem</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/posftix-permission-denied-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 02:18:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/posftix-permission-denied-problem/</guid><description>Recently I stuck with WordPress installation which was unable to send emails using build in wp_mail function.
After investigation tail -f /var/log/messages I founded a pleasant line of code with really nice explanation:
sendmail: fatal: chdir /var/spool/postfix: Permission denied
In theory this should be a problem for sysadmin, but – I wanted to find faster solution.
After short adventure with Google I found a clue:
/usr/sbin/getsebool httpd_can_sendmail
My result was obvious:</description></item><item><title>Attribute value in Magento</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/attribute-value-in-magento/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 02:37:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/attribute-value-in-magento/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some useful function for managing attribute values in Magento.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More about product attributes in Magento</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/more-about-product-attributes-in-magento/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 05:10:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/more-about-product-attributes-in-magento/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last time I mentioned Magento attributes, how to create them from model. Ok – but examples was quite simple. This time a little more explanation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento get all categories into array</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-get-all-categories-into-array/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:26:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-get-all-categories-into-array/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can grab all existing categories in Magento to array, here is quick example:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter IMG – thumbnails</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/codeigniter-img-thumbnails-on-the-fly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 04:20:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/codeigniter-img-thumbnails-on-the-fly/</guid><description>CodeIgniter library to generate high-quality thumbnails A library is based on excellent * Smarty plugin “Thumb” * created in 2005 by Christoph Erdmann. This version is a little bit different, we are using the core from Thumb, and some modification which gives more flexibility to work with it.
Features thumbnails are generated “on the fly” no additional actions required, cache for generated thumbnails, a clear structure for generated thumbnails, thumbnails sharpening function, cropping function, fill space function Usage You need to upload a file img.</description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter minify</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/codeigniter-minify/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 04:08:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/codeigniter-minify/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simple library to minify JavaScript &amp;amp; CSS in CodeIgniter. JavaScript minification is based on
&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/closure/compiler/">Closure Compiler&lt;/a>
. CSS minifcation is based on
&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/minify/">minify library&lt;/a>
. Addtionaly all CSS scripts and JavaScript scripts are marget into single files.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>XCache driver CodeIgniter</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/xcache-driver-codeigniter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 03:51:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/projects/xcache-driver-codeigniter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is a missing
&lt;a href="http://xcache.lighttpd.net/">XCache&lt;/a>
driver for
&lt;a href="http://codeigniter.com/user_guide/libraries/caching.html">CodeIgniter Caching Class&lt;/a>
. All You need to do is to modify &lt;code>/system/libraries/Cache/Cache.php&lt;/code> library and add additional Cache driver to drivers list:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento read / write config values from model</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-read-write-config-values-from-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 04:23:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-read-write-config-values-from-model/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can create Magento config settings using XML files, or… do this directly from model. Here is example:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento generate url from model</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-generate-url-from-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 04:16:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-generate-url-from-model/</guid><description>&lt;p>All links in Magento should be generated via url model. Here is simple examples working in backend.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento manage attributes from model</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-manage-attributes-from-model/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 04:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-manage-attributes-from-model/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can create and remove Magento product attributes from model. It’s quite simple if you know how.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter IMG – thumbnails on the fly</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/codeigniter-img-thumbnails-on-the-fly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 20:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/codeigniter-img-thumbnails-on-the-fly/</guid><description>CodeIgniter library to generate high quality thumbnails
Library is based on excellent * Smarty plugin “Thumb” * created in 2005 by Christoph Erdmann. This version is a little different, we are using core from Thumb, and some modification which gives more flexibility to work with it.
Features thumbnails are generated “on the fly” no additional actions required, cache for generated thumbnails, clear structure for generated thumbnails, thumbnails sharpening function, cropping function, fill space function Usage You need to upload file img.</description></item><item><title>How to create Screen Cast on Mac OS X</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-create-screen-cast-under-mac-os-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 18:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-create-screen-cast-under-mac-os-x/</guid><description>Sometimes you can’t create only description. Sometimes you need to record a screen cast on your Mac OS X. Under Windows environment I used excelent simple program called WINK. It is really simple, fast and efficient solution for creating screen cast using Windows. Unfortunately I didn’t found any similar solution for Mac until now… It’s also really simple and it called: Jing.</description></item><item><title>Google Storage for Developers vs Amazon S3</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-storage-for-developers-vs-amazon-s3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:35:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-storage-for-developers-vs-amazon-s3/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just got activation for
&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/apis/storage/">Google Storage for Developers&lt;/a>
. Service is similar to
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon S3&lt;/a>
but it’s served by Google and it’s still in beta mode – that’s mean that you can’t just register and use, and you have limited warranty about quality and uptime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Desktop Closure Compiler beta release</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/desktop-closure-compiler-beta-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 03:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/desktop-closure-compiler-beta-release/</guid><description>The Closure Compileris a tool for making JavaScript download and run faster. It is a true compiler for JavaScript. Instead of compiling from a source language to machine code, it compiles from JavaScript to better JavaScript. It parses your JavaScript, analyzes it, removes dead code and rewrites and minimizes what’s left. It also checks syntax, variable references, and types, and warns about common JavaScript pitfalls.
Google provides Closure Compiler Servicewhich is web application to compile JavaScript, you can also use Java application or REST API.</description></item><item><title>Website maintenance</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/website-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 07:51:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/website-maintenance/</guid><description>Website Maintenance So you have a website… but do you struggle to keep the content fresh and relevant to users? Maybe you’re confused about the technical side of keeping your website up-to-date, or simply don’t have the time to do it yourself?
We can support you with reliable, timely and cost effective website maintenance services.
Examples of website changes which we can do for you:
product changes and additions, add breaking news or upcoming events to keep your site up to date add photos, graphics, graphs and charts to keep you site fresh add analytics codes so you can track your sites metrics (with Google Analytics or Piwik ) What about CMS?</description></item><item><title>Dedicated Content Management System for kindergarten</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/dedicated-cms-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 03:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/dedicated-cms-system/</guid><description>Recently we finished dedicated content management system for bilingual kindergarten and school. Whole project includes intranet for parents, where they can find recent information about theirs children’s, information about upcoming events and photo galleries from past events. Some screenshots below.</description></item><item><title>MySQL on Mac OS X with preference panel</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/mysql-on-mac-os-x-with-preference-panel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 10:06:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/mysql-on-mac-os-x-with-preference-panel/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my daily work I really suffered because MySQL wasn’t work after fresh installation. Preference panel just didn’t start MySQL on system startup neither using it into Preferences.&lt;br>
After a lot of google research I found many solutions but only
&lt;a href="http://www.angry-fly.com/post.cfm/getting-mysql-preference-pane-to-work-in-leopard">Angry Fly&lt;/a>
gives me some clues how to find proper fix.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter OpenSource Web Application Framework</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/codeigniter-opensource-web-application-framework/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 10:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/codeigniter-opensource-web-application-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p>For many years we was searching for for really good
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framework">framework&lt;/a>
for our application core. After trying &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Zend Framework&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> which is really power-full, but quite heavy for regular use, we tried to use some lighter – &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->CakePHP&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> which is better, but still many solutions are to complicated for real rapid development and freedom, we found what we are looking for – &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->CodeIgniter&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple FAQ WordPress plugin</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/simple-faq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 09:26:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/simple-faq/</guid><description>Simple FAQ gives you ability to create very simple FAQ on your site (questions and answers).
You can add question and answer using WordPress panel.
Read more on WordPress Simple FAQ plugin page.
Installation Unzip the package and upload the Simple FAQ directory into your wp-content/plugins directory of your WordPress installation. Activate the plugin at the plugin from plugins page. Put the short code [display_faq] in your page. Because that is general idea.</description></item><item><title>Content Management Systems</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/web-content-management-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 05:05:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/web-content-management-system/</guid><description>A Web Content Management System (WCMS) is a software system which provides website authoring and administration tools designed to allow users with little knowledge of web programming languages or markup languages to create and manage the site’s content with relative ease.
In most cases system use a database to store content, but this not a rule. Sometimes if website is simple CMS allows you only change content od static HTML files.</description></item><item><title>Content Management System for BISK</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/content-management-system-for-bisk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 03:28:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/content-management-system-for-bisk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Content Management System for BISK is highly customised solution for website management in many languages. Thousands products to browse, with technical details and pictures in easy form to browse and see.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 02:05:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/about/</guid><description>SpiderSoft is an Australian software development company. We have presence in Sydney and offshore offices in Poland. We are specializing in custom software solutions.
With a development methodology refined over 10 years, SpiderSoft can provide fully supported custom software. Take advantage of our expertise in building applications for web, desktop, and mobile.
Areas where are specialized in:
New Application Development Upgrade Of Legacy Systems Maintenance &amp;amp; Enhancement Custom Application Integration Check out our OpenSource PROJECTS and GET IN TOUCH !</description></item><item><title>Classified Ad System</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/classified-ad-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 17:18:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/classified-ad-system/</guid><description>&lt;p>Classified Ad System is web application which allows you to create unlimited classified ad website. Easy to deploy and use, SEO ready. Users can post their advertisement with images and description.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/contact-us/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 16:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/contact-us/</guid><description>SpiderSoft,
Suite 703, Level 7
The Trust Building
155 King Street
Sydney NSW 2000
AUSTRALIA
ABN: 84 642 337 578
DUNS: 743856067
Call us: +61 2 8294 2032
SpiderSoft is a an Australian business operating in Sydney since 2010.
Fell free to send us any kind of questions.</description></item><item><title>Piwik as a alternative to Google Analytics</title><link>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/piwik-as-a-alternative-to-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 21:41:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/piwik-as-a-alternative-to-google-analytics/</guid><description>Piwik is a downloadable, open source (GPL licensed) real time web analytics software program. It provides you with detailed reports on your website visitors: the search engines and keywords they used, the language they speak, your popular pages… and so much more.
It’s great free open source alternative for Google Analytics. It’s easier and more readably for regular user to understand traffic on your website.
What makes Piwik unique from the competition:</description></item></channel></rss>