<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Case studies on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/categories/case-studies/</link><description>Recent content in Case studies on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 08:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/categories/case-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automated email parser</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/automated-email-parser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 08:43:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/automated-email-parser/</guid><description>It’s a simple mechanic to decompose emails into useful parts, like some markup (to squiz emails directly into internal systems) and create file attachments – and extract inline images.
Flow is pretty simple, but we have couple components.
We need something to “receive” emails. Easiest way is to use Amazon SES or mailgun or… something else. There is a couple SASS solutions for that Next step is to be notified when email arrive, so we don’t have overhead with checking email every couple of minutes We have to “decompose” – decode email from it’s raw format to text, and attachments.</description></item><item><title>How to make email work better email2issue</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-make-email-work-better-email2issue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/how-to-make-email-work-better-email2issue/</guid><description>&lt;p>The problem:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are using bug tracking system, as most of the software development companies. Creating an issue is quite simple. Open bug tracking system, fill some inputs, upload attachments – done. Issue is created. Sometimes issue is described with multiple attachments (screenshots). Bug tracking system allows us to embed images into description.  All issues come from users in a form of email.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>