<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/categories/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:42:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Centralized Authentication with lldap: A Practical Guide</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2026/ldap-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:42:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2026/ldap-practical-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-problem-does-this-solve"&gt;What problem does this solve?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re running a homelab or a small infrastructure with multiple self-hosted services, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably hit this wall: every service has its own user database. Nextcloud has one, Gitea has another, Portainer has its own, and so on. Add a new team member? You&amp;rsquo;re creating accounts in five different places. Someone leaves? Good luck remembering where they had access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDAP solves this by giving you a &lt;strong&gt;single directory&lt;/strong&gt; where all your users and groups live. Each service connects to this directory instead of maintaining its own user list. You create a user once, assign them to groups, and every connected service knows who they are and what they can access.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloudflare Tunnel: A Modern Alternative to Ngrok</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/posts/2025-01-16-ngrok-alternative/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/posts/2025-01-16-ngrok-alternative/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="quick-and-free-way-to-share-your-local-docker-service-with-clients"&gt;Quick and Free Way to Share Your Local Docker Service with Clients&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever been in that situation where you&amp;rsquo;ve built something cool in Docker and want to quickly show it to your client? Yeah, me too. Recently, I was wrapping up a database admin panel project and needed a way to let my client review it before the final deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My go-to solution used to be Ngrok. It works, but the free tier gives you random URLs that look like &lt;code&gt;8f4d-192-158-1-38.ngrok.io&lt;/code&gt;. Not very professional when sending to clients, right? Plus, these URLs change every time you restart the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>