<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:09:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>4 reasons why you don’t get a new client Today</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/4-reasons-why-you-dont-get-a-new-client-today/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2018/4-reasons-why-you-dont-get-a-new-client-today/</guid><description>Each day – new companies want to make the world a better place and try to sell you fantastic service, API, whatever. I’m constantly searching for new exciting, and valuable services which could make “my” (my clients) live easier. Everyone has a flashy website, “Try now”, “Try now for free”, “Signup for free” – fill the form, no credit card required… entry level – no trouble at all. Let’s do it.</description></item><item><title>How to choose the right technology for your next project</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/how-to-choose-the-right-technology-for-your-next-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 06:41:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/how-to-choose-the-right-technology-for-your-next-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>People quite often asking me about &lt;em>technology stack&lt;/em>, and where to go with next big project. The answer isn’t simple – it depends. Usually, we have couple components which are critical for the whole system. If we are talking about a web-based solution or any API we have to decide about DATABASE, then we have STORAGE, moving on – some BACKEND service language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Dev libraries – week 21</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/this-week-findings-in-webdev-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:48:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/this-week-findings-in-webdev-21/</guid><description>I’m consuming enormous amount of news each day. These is list of my findings from just only these week.
Envision.js is a library for creating fast, dynamic and interactive HTML5 visualisations.
Apy is a simple client-side library for making rest api ajax calls.
Sitespeed.io is an open source tool that helps you analyse your website speed and performance based on performance best practices and metrics. It collects data from multiple pages on your website, analyze the pages using the rules and output the result as HTML or JUnit XML.</description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter-minify update</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/codeigniter-minify-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/codeigniter-minify-update/</guid><description>Just introduce some new options to my quite popular library CodeIgniter-minify . From now one you can chose CSS compression engine (cssmin || minify), also FORCE rewrite CSS files. Some speed improvements were also made.
Please feel to checkout library on GitGub – CodeIgniter-minify</description></item><item><title>Quote of the day</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/quote-of-the-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 04:35:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/quote-of-the-day/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The easiest way to share files within same network</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/the-easiest-way-to-share-files-within-same-network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 04:51:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/the-easiest-way-to-share-files-within-same-network/</guid><description>Sometimes you are just to lazy to copy files to local storage server. Sending files over email ? To long. What other options you have.
If you are on Mac – AirDrop is an answer but – you have to be on wireless. What if you are using old fashion cable ?
There is a solution for that – web experiment called www.sharedrop.io ShareDrop is a free app that allows you to easily and securely share files directly between devices in the same local network*, without having to upload them to any server first.</description></item><item><title>My daily struggle</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/fun-with-css/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/fun-with-css/</guid><description>&amp;lt;img loading=&amp;ldquo;lazy&amp;rdquo; alt=&amp;ldquo;Daily struggle&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;ldquo; https://d1e24pw9mnwsl8.cloudfront.net/c/css.gif&amp;#34; width=&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;460&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Why AWS is better than Rackspace</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m huge fan fan ow
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com">AWS&lt;/a>
services. It just works – don’t need any kind of support, prices are really good. No issues whatsoever. But – of course my nature ask me to check out other options. For example
&lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com.au/">Rackspace&lt;/a>
. So I registered account, filled out my business and credit details. Just to give a small background – got registered business since 2011 in Australia. I filled out my CC details, phone number and so on. Pretty standard process. I logged in, and start playing with their interface (pretty slow, but I shouldn’t complain yet). The best is about to come…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to force jQuery version on WordPress</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-force-jquery-version-on-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 11:35:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-force-jquery-version-on-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another really simple code snippet. This time, we are trying to force particular version of jQuery injecting into WordPress.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cut and slice Photoshop files really easy</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/cut-and-slice-photoshop-really-easy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 23:34:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/cut-and-slice-photoshop-really-easy/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is one if these rare plugins which make my live lot easier. Actually can’t imagine my work without it. 
&lt;a href="http://www.cutandslice.me/">Cut&amp;amp;Slice me&lt;/a>
 is able to export your assets to different devices in seconds. Whole idea is really simple – name objects, or groups in special way. Click one button – and all assets will be exported in proper file names. It’s getting event better – his plugin is able to export all assets in multiple dimensions (retina images). So… if you ever dreamt about perfect tool for you work – this is it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CSS Sprites online tools</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/css-sprites-online-tools/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 10:26:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/css-sprites-online-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sprite_%28computer_graphics%29#Sprites_by_CSS">CSS Sprites&lt;/a>
 it was a very popular technique for a long time. Biggest benefit from it: reduce number of the requestes to the server, and speedup whole website / loading image assets. Working with CSS slides is really painful  Usually you are starting from PSD then you have to decouple them to separate images, then merge them again to one image, and then mark position of each element in the CSS file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Couple useful tools to work with:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gearman installation on CentOS and AMI Linux</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/gearman-installation-on-centos-and-ami-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 01:53:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/gearman-installation-on-centos-and-ami-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="http://gearman.org/">Gearman&lt;/a>
provides a generic application framework to farm out work to other machines or processes that are better suited to do the work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This solution is truly multiplatform, so we have Client API and Wordkres in multiple languages like Shell, Perl, NodeJS any couple of others (PHP!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PhpStorm 5 Released</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/phpstorm-5-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 05:24:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/phpstorm-5-released/</guid><description>PhpStorm is great PHP IDE for all kind of web development practices. JetBrains just release latest version 5.0. List of changes is quite long, my recommendation is to read what’s new list.</description></item><item><title>Sublime2 favourite configuration</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/sublime2-favourite-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 11:01:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/sublime2-favourite-configuration/</guid><description>&lt;p>As long as I’m not huge fan of
&lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text 2&lt;/a>
– I have to admin it’s really fast. This is the fastest editor which I ever seen. So – for quick edit I’m usually using it. But there are 2 annoying default settings which I really can’t stand: opening each file in new tab, and moving to the end of the file on “end” keystroke. Finally I founded how to solve my daily problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Easy wireframes with Moqups</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/easy-wireframes-with-moqups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 12:50:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/easy-wireframes-with-moqups/</guid><description>Creating wireframes is a very tedious job, but now there is new webapp for that – unfortunately you don’t have to use iPhone to make really easy and quick wireframes. Only think which you need is only HTML5 browser, and a little bit of free time. Check it now: Moqups</description></item><item><title>Amazon AWS finally in Australia</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</guid><description>Finally we can enjoy power and speed of Amazon AWS services, in Australia but… so far we can’t get full experience, it’s only for two services – Amazon Route 53 and Amazon CloudFront . So… in simple words we can enjoy with 100% SLA DNS service and global CDN with edge location based on Sydney.</description></item><item><title>Amazon RDS for $20 monthly</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-rds-for-20-monthly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 07:52:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-rds-for-20-monthly/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon AWS
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2012/06/11/amazon-rds-micro/">just announced&lt;/a>
that Micro instances can be used for
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/rds/">Amazon RDS&lt;/a>
with MySQL database engine which is really good news. Previously cheapest option  was Small Instance which was quite “expensive” with $0.105 USD for on hour (without reserved instances). Now we can use RDS with MySQL for $0.025 hourly! We can go even lower with reserved instances. Details about pricing are
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/rds/pricing/">available here&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web thumbnails for free</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/web-thumbnails-for-free/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 23:45:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/web-thumbnails-for-free/</guid><description>Taking snapshots of websites – it’s very simple thing, but … you need to install an browser extension – I’m using Awesome Screenshot , or use magic shortcut in Mac OS X. You can also take advantage of services specializing in this task, but as far as I know there are not many free solutions. So today I will describe the project webthumbnail.org .&amp;lt;/
The idea is very simple – generate snapshots of the page at any resolution, we can choose between several browsers (Chrome, FireFox, Opera).</description></item><item><title>Mac OS X Window Manager</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/mac-os-x-window-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 08:08:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/mac-os-x-window-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was looking for some kind of easy to use Window Manager for Mac OS X. Usually I’m working on multiple screen with multiple application open (usually it’s between 4-8). It’s really hard to organise everything in proper order and placement. Arranging windows it’s slow, especially when you need to compare or see results on multiple window at once.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iBrowser and TinyMCE</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/ibrowser-and-tinymce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 12:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/ibrowser-and-tinymce/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can find plenty of tutorials how to setup tinyMCE and iBrowser, but non of them mention about common problems, like “error building image list!”, or how to bind regular image browser to iBrowser. Here you can find full instructions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WordPress starter theme – Foundation</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/wordpress-starter-theme-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 18:33:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/wordpress-starter-theme-foundation/</guid><description> Foundation is a rapid prototyping and building library from ZURB. Which is basically great CSS framework. Light, quick in development and good looking. In last days I just discover great based starter theme based on this CSS framework – check it out Foundation for WordPress or just download directly from GitHub</description></item><item><title>Apache Virtual Hosts in a Database</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/apache-virtual-hosts-in-a-database/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/apache-virtual-hosts-in-a-database/</guid><description>&lt;p>As much as I love
&lt;a href="http://www.lighttpd.net/">lighttpd&lt;/a>
 sometimes I can’t avoid
&lt;a href="http://httpd.apache.org/">Apache&lt;/a>
. For me – “the best” thing in lighttpd is support for keeping vhost names in MySQL database. I don’t have to use any config files, I can just put record into MySQL database with virtual host server name, path to document root and it’s done. But – I can do the same witch Apache! How? With third party modules, below you can find short tutorial “how to”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter Uploadify problem</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/codeigniter-uploadify-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 02:37:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/codeigniter-uploadify-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>I tried to implement Uploadify with
&lt;a href="http://codeigniter.com/user_guide/libraries/file_uploading.html">CodeIgniter upload class&lt;/a>
, and had some issues with recognising proper mime types.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to get better results with ImageMagick and convert</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-get-better-results-with-imagemagick-and-convert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 23:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-get-better-results-with-imagemagick-and-convert/</guid><description>In last two days I’m trying to find best way to convert PDF files to good quality JPEG files. Of course size does matter, not only in case of women breasts.
When I was trying convert files directly from PDF to JPEG results was pretty scary:
convert myfile.pdf[1] dc.jpg
number 1 in brackets means only one(second) page to process.
As I result I get file with pretty huge size: 496.8K</description></item><item><title>Lighttpd and upload_max_filesize</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-upload_max_filesize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 01:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-upload_max_filesize/</guid><description>Default setting for uploading file size in PHP is really small. Usually it’s about 2MB. To increase this limit, you need to change one obvious variable:
upload_max_filesize = 20M Eventually you can also increase max number of files to upload:
max_file_uploads = 20 But… this is not enough. Because on lighttpd PHP is working as a FastCGI process when you start uploading bigger files, you can get this bad message:</description></item><item><title>Google mod-pagespeed on CentOS</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-mod-pagespeed-on-centos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:48:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-mod-pagespeed-on-centos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Short “How to” install Google mod-pagespeed on CentOs. You can read more about this Apache module on this page: Google
&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/speed/page-speed/docs/module.html">mod_pagespeed overview&lt;/a>
. Basicly it’s a module which gives your website speedup. Many simple techniques to reduce size and number of requests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lighttpd and mod_expire</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-mod_expire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 03:39:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/lighttpd-and-mod_expire/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google
&lt;a href="http://pagespeed.googlelabs.com/">Page Speed Online&lt;/a>
is really good service for measuring and optimising your website. After deep analysis we get a lot if clues how to improve speed of your website. But how to
&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/speed/page-speed/docs/caching.html#LeverageBrowserCaching">Leverage browser caching&lt;/a>
if we have
&lt;a href="http://www.lighttpd.net/">Lighttpd&lt;/a>
 instead default Apache? We need to use
&lt;a href="http://redmine.lighttpd.net/wiki/lighttpd/Docs:ModExpire">mod_expire&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drupal and lighttpd mod_rewrite settings</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/drupal-and-lighttpd-mod_rewrite-settings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 03:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/drupal-and-lighttpd-mod_rewrite-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lighttpd is awesome and very fast webserver. But has one big disadvantage – is not reading apache .htaccess files with rewrite settings. Unfortunatley you need to create them manually in config file. How? Examples are below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Posftix Permission denied problem</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/posftix-permission-denied-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 02:18:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/posftix-permission-denied-problem/</guid><description>Recently I stuck with WordPress installation which was unable to send emails using build in wp_mail function.
After investigation tail -f /var/log/messages I founded a pleasant line of code with really nice explanation:
sendmail: fatal: chdir /var/spool/postfix: Permission denied
In theory this should be a problem for sysadmin, but – I wanted to find faster solution.
After short adventure with Google I found a clue:
/usr/sbin/getsebool httpd_can_sendmail
My result was obvious:</description></item><item><title>More about product attributes in Magento</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/more-about-product-attributes-in-magento/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 05:10:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/more-about-product-attributes-in-magento/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last time I mentioned Magento attributes, how to create them from model. Ok – but examples was quite simple. This time a little more explanation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento get all categories into array</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-get-all-categories-into-array/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:26:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-get-all-categories-into-array/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can grab all existing categories in Magento to array, here is quick example:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento generate url from model</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-generate-url-from-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 04:16:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-generate-url-from-model/</guid><description>&lt;p>All links in Magento should be generated via url model. Here is simple examples working in backend.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magento manage attributes from model</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-manage-attributes-from-model/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 04:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/magento-manage-attributes-from-model/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can create and remove Magento product attributes from model. It’s quite simple if you know how.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter IMG – thumbnails on the fly</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/codeigniter-img-thumbnails-on-the-fly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 20:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/codeigniter-img-thumbnails-on-the-fly/</guid><description>CodeIgniter library to generate high quality thumbnails
Library is based on excellent * Smarty plugin “Thumb” * created in 2005 by Christoph Erdmann. This version is a little different, we are using core from Thumb, and some modification which gives more flexibility to work with it.
Features thumbnails are generated “on the fly” no additional actions required, cache for generated thumbnails, clear structure for generated thumbnails, thumbnails sharpening function, cropping function, fill space function Usage You need to upload file img.</description></item><item><title>How to create Screen Cast on Mac OS X</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-create-screen-cast-under-mac-os-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 18:37:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-create-screen-cast-under-mac-os-x/</guid><description>Sometimes you can’t create only description. Sometimes you need to record a screen cast on your Mac OS X. Under Windows environment I used excelent simple program called WINK . It is really simple, fast and efficient solution for creating screen cast using Windows. Unfortunately I didn’t found any similar solution for Mac until now… It’s also really simple and it called: Jing .</description></item><item><title>Google Storage for Developers vs Amazon S3</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-storage-for-developers-vs-amazon-s3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:35:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-storage-for-developers-vs-amazon-s3/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just got activation for
&lt;a href="http://code.google.com/apis/storage/">Google Storage for Developers&lt;/a>
. Service is similar to
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon S3&lt;/a>
but it’s served by Google and it’s still in beta mode – that’s mean that you can’t just register and use, and you have limited warranty about quality and uptime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MySQL on Mac OS X with preference panel</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/mysql-on-mac-os-x-with-preference-panel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 10:06:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/mysql-on-mac-os-x-with-preference-panel/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my daily work I really suffered because MySQL wasn’t work after fresh installation. Preference panel just didn’t start MySQL on system startup neither using it into Preferences.&lt;br>
After a lot of google research I found many solutions but only
&lt;a href="http://www.angry-fly.com/post.cfm/getting-mysql-preference-pane-to-work-in-leopard">Angry Fly&lt;/a>
gives me some clues how to find proper fix.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CodeIgniter OpenSource Web Application Framework</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/codeigniter-opensource-web-application-framework/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 10:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2010/codeigniter-opensource-web-application-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p>For many years we was searching for for really good
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Framework">framework&lt;/a>
for our application core. After trying
&lt;a href="http://framework.zend.com/">Zend Framework&lt;/a>
which is really power-full, but quite heavy for regular use, we tried to use some lighter –
&lt;a href="http://cakephp.org/">CakePHP&lt;/a>
which is better, but still many solutions are to complicated for real rapid development and freedom, we found what we are looking for –
&lt;a href="http://codeigniter.com/">CodeIgniter&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>