<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>For Agencies on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/</link><description>Recent content in For Agencies on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 07:51:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Website maintenance</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/website-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 07:51:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/website-maintenance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="website-maintenance"&gt;Website Maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have a website… but do you struggle to keep the content fresh and relevant to users? Maybe you’re confused about the technical side of keeping your website up-to-date, or simply don’t have the time to do it yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can support you with reliable, timely and cost effective &lt;strong&gt;website maintenance&lt;/strong&gt; services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of &lt;strong&gt;website changes&lt;/strong&gt; which we can do for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;product changes and additions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add breaking news or upcoming events to keep your site up to date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add photos, graphics, graphs and charts to keep you site fresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add analytics codes so you can track your sites metrics (with Google Analytics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-about-cms"&gt; What about CMS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of a content management system is that you can easily &lt;strong&gt;maintain a website&lt;/strong&gt; using the software, which is often derived free from a community of online developers and designers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Content Management Systems</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/web-content-management-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 05:05:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/services/web-content-management-system/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Web Content Management System&lt;/strong&gt; (WCMS) is a software system which provides website authoring and administration tools designed to allow users with little knowledge of web programming languages or markup languages to create and manage the site’s content with relative ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most cases system use a database to store content, but this not a rule. Sometimes if website is simple CMS allows you only change content od static HTML files.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>