<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>image on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/tags/image/</link><description>Recent content in image on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 06:16:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/tags/image/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docker, GO and CGO application build</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/docker-go-cgo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 06:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2021/docker-go-cgo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been avoid Docker for a very long time. I started my career as a sysadmin setting up servers running FreeBSD and early versions of Debian on bare-bone servers. As soon as “cloud” came into to the market I switch to AWS, and GCE and have been using them since then. EC2 was my always goto choice to quickly deploy something on the internet. But Docker — from some reason I was avoiding it until this 2 years ago, when I actually started using it. Without to much trust but…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But today history is not about my love &amp;amp; hate relationship with docker, but about trying to deploy Go application and VIPS library. Couple problems appeared during the process and it’s worth mentioning it for future generations because could find much help around my issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web thumbnails for free</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/web-thumbnails-for-free/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 23:45:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/web-thumbnails-for-free/</guid><description>Taking snapshots of websites – it’s very simple thing, but … you need to install an browser extension – I’m using Awesome Screenshot , or use magic shortcut in Mac OS X. You can also take advantage of services specializing in this task, but as far as I know there are not many free solutions. So today I will describe the project webthumbnail.org .&amp;lt;/
The idea is very simple – generate snapshots of the page at any resolution, we can choose between several browsers (Chrome, FireFox, Opera).</description></item><item><title>How to get better results with ImageMagick and convert</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-get-better-results-with-imagemagick-and-convert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 23:33:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/how-to-get-better-results-with-imagemagick-and-convert/</guid><description>In last two days I’m trying to find best way to convert PDF files to good quality JPEG files. Of course size does matter, not only in case of women breasts.
When I was trying convert files directly from PDF to JPEG results was pretty scary:
convert myfile.pdf[1] dc.jpg
number 1 in brackets means only one(second) page to process.
As I result I get file with pretty huge size: 496.8K</description></item></channel></rss>