<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 10:46:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When you are running out of space on your server</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/when-you-are-running-out-of-space-on-your-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 10:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/when-you-are-running-out-of-space-on-your-server/</guid><description>…in most cases you have 2 options. Because we are living in Cloud and VPS era – it’s not a big deal. You can always bump up your volume and after while you can enjoy bigger more expensive instance with more space. But sometimes you need just a space for a while or… just something for a backup ? You can always use s3cmd , gsutil or another tool. Imagine that you have just regular folder on your drive, with almost unlimited space.</description></item><item><title>Free virtual machines with Internet Explorer</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/free-virtual-machines-with-internet-explorer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 05:22:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/free-virtual-machines-with-internet-explorer/</guid><description> BrowserStack is well known service which provides awesome tools to test your website against different browsers and operating systems. It’s very handy when it comes to professional QA testing.
Not everyone knows, that from that place you can also download virtual machines for free. On this page Virtual Machine you can pull multiple VM images with IE8 / IE 9 and different versions of windows.
 </description></item><item><title>Why AWS is better than Rackspace</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m huge fan fan ow
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com">AWS&lt;/a>
services. It just works – don’t need any kind of support, prices are really good. No issues whatsoever. But – of course my nature ask me to check out other options. For example
&lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com.au/">Rackspace&lt;/a>
. So I registered account, filled out my business and credit details. Just to give a small background – got registered business since 2011 in Australia. I filled out my CC details, phone number and so on. Pretty standard process. I logged in, and start playing with their interface (pretty slow, but I shouldn’t complain yet). The best is about to come…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I don’t recommend mailgun…</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-i-dont-recommend-mailgun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 23:26:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-i-dont-recommend-mailgun/</guid><description>Couple months ago I listed services having API for sending and receiving emails . One of them was mailgun – I was using it for a while since… yesterday. My account was locked without any valid reason. Something related with SPAM:
http://documentation.mailgun.com/razor.html Reference: #rzr01.
Because I know exactly what emails are being sent using my accounts (I keep track of each email coming out from the system) I was really interested how it could happen.</description></item><item><title>Amazon AWS finally in Australia</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</guid><description>Finally we can enjoy power and speed of Amazon AWS services, in Australia but… so far we can’t get full experience, it’s only for two services – Amazon Route 53 and Amazon CloudFront . So… in simple words we can enjoy with 100% SLA DNS service and global CDN with edge location based on Sydney.</description></item><item><title>Amazon RDS for $20 monthly</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-rds-for-20-monthly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 07:52:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-rds-for-20-monthly/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon AWS
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2012/06/11/amazon-rds-micro/">just announced&lt;/a>
that Micro instances can be used for
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/rds/">Amazon RDS&lt;/a>
with MySQL database engine which is really good news. Previously cheapest option  was Small Instance which was quite “expensive” with $0.105 USD for on hour (without reserved instances). Now we can use RDS with MySQL for $0.025 hourly! We can go even lower with reserved instances. Details about pricing are
&lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/rds/pricing/">available here&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>