<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aws on SpiderSoft</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on SpiderSoft</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Restore Files from Glacier on Amazon S3 Storage using Bash Script</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2023/how-to-restore-objects-from-glacier-with-a-script/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2023/how-to-restore-objects-from-glacier-with-a-script/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon S3 storage is a popular cloud storage service that provides scalable object storage for data backup, archive, and disaster recovery. One of the storage options available on Amazon S3 is Amazon Glacier, which provides a low-cost, long-term storage solution for data archiving and backup. However, retrieving data from Amazon Glacier can be time-consuming and expensive. In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to restore files from Glacier on Amazon S3 storage using a Bash script.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to test golang written lambda function locally</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/how-to-test-lambda-function-locally/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/how-to-test-lambda-function-locally/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while I was looking for an easy we to test my lambda functions written in golang locally. We have awesome tools like 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://localstack.cloud/">LocalStack&lt;/a>
 but this is not what I was looking for. I wanted to test my lambda function locally, without any dependencies. Something lighter without 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker&lt;/a>
 . I will show you how to do that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to host static website on AWS CloudFront</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/how-to-host-static-website-on-aws-cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/how-to-host-static-website-on-aws-cloudfront/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was looking for a way to host a static website on AWS. I found a couple of ways to do that. I decided to use CloudFront as a CDN and S3 as an origin. I will show you how to do that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to create AWS Signature on GET POST request</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/aws-signature-request/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/aws-signature-request/</guid><description>&lt;p>Postman, it&amp;rsquo;s a great tool for debuging, testing and other activities performed by us - developers. It has a build in option to sign requestes with 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://learning.postman.com/docs/sending-requests/authorization/#aws-signature">AWS Signature&lt;/a>
 . We do have 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2">AWS SDK for Go v2&lt;/a>
 , but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any good examples except a 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/blob/main/aws/signer/v4/v4_test.go">test file&lt;/a>
 . The other useful file will be 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/blob/main/aws/signer/internal/v4/const.go">const.go&lt;/a>
 where we can find a couple of interesting variables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to upload to S3 with presigned URL</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/upload-with-presigned-url-to-bucket/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2022/upload-with-presigned-url-to-bucket/</guid><description>&lt;p>Object storage is getting more and more popular. AWS started, but nowadays, almost every provider has it. Recently 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/introducing-r2-object-storage/">Cloudflare&lt;/a>
 announced its availability. 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/products/spaces">DigitalOcean&lt;/a>
 call them Spaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So today, we are trying to upload a file to an S3 type of storage with a presigned URL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TL;DR: how to generate the correct URL and upload data into it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fastest way to install Tesseract on EC2</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/fastest-way-to-install-tesseract-on-ec2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 12:03:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/fastest-way-to-install-tesseract-on-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p> 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract">Tesseract&lt;/a>
 it’s a great library Open Source library to supply free OCR solutions for multiple libraries. You can use it directly from command line, or in your own software using supplied libraries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automated email parser</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/automated-email-parser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 08:43:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2019/automated-email-parser/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a simple mechanic to decompose emails into valuable parts, like some markup (to push emails directly into internal systems), create file attachments and extract inline images.
Flow is pretty simple, but we have a couple of components.
We need something to “receive” emails. The easiest way is to use Amazon SES or mailgun or… something else. There are a couple of SASS solutions for that. Next step is to be notified when the email arrives, so we don’t have overhead with checking email every couple of minutes We have to “decompose” – decode email from it’s raw format to text, and attachments.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with AWS CLI</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/getting-started-with-aws-cli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 07:25:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/getting-started-with-aws-cli/</guid><description>&lt;p>AWS has extremely nice UI. But – with the time, you need to do something faster than just clicking via an interface. Sometimes you need to automate something (start/stop instances, make a backup. If you are wondering – there is a perfect time for CLI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SWAP space on EC2 on separate volume</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/swap-space-on-ec2-on-separate-volume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 04:27:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/swap-space-on-ec2-on-separate-volume/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s an extension of my previous article – how to create 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/ec2-instance-and-swap-space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SWAP on EC2 instance.&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, we are going to create separate volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When you are running out of space on your server</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/when-you-are-running-out-of-space-on-your-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 10:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2017/when-you-are-running-out-of-space-on-your-server/</guid><description>…in most cases you have 2 options. Because we are living in Cloud and VPS era – it’s not a big deal. You can always bump up your volume and after while you can enjoy bigger more expensive instance with more space. But sometimes you need just a space for a while or… just something for a backup ? You can always use s3cmd , gsutil or another tool. Imagine that you have just regular folder on your drive, with almost unlimited space.</description></item><item><title>How schedule start and stop EC2 instance on AWS</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-schedule-start-and-stop-ec2-instance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 14:53:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2016/how-schedule-start-and-stop-ec2-instance-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Biggest advantage with AWS – EC2 service, is that you are paying for each minute of usage. So – why run instances 24/7 if you need them only for 12 hours par day ? You can just start and stop whenever you need them. Obviously we don’t want to forgot to shutdown our instance, or start when we need it. Here is a simple recipe how to automate whole task&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PHP 7 on AMI Linux (EC2)</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/php-7-on-ami-linux-ec2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 14:34:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/php-7-on-ami-linux-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p>PHP 7.0 it&amp;rsquo;s already a while on the market. Let’s install it on EC2 instance.  Here you can find a quick recipe:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to install latest golang on EC2</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/how-to-install-latest-golang-on-ec2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 11:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/how-to-install-latest-golang-on-ec2/</guid><description>If you are looking for simple way to upgrade yourt golang installation on EC2, you can experience error like that:
Error: Package: golang-bin-1.5.1-0.el6.x86_64 (epel) Requires: go = 1.5.1-0.el6 Installing: golang-1.4.2-3.19.amzn1.x86_64 (amzn-main) Because on amzn-main repo, there is an older version of golang – on epel, there is a newer. Nothing simplier just disable for a momement amzn-main repo, and install golang compeltly from epel.
sudo yum --disablerepo=amzn-main --enablerepo=epel install golang-bin</description></item><item><title>Using Google Cloud storage with AWS libraries in GO LANG</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/google-cloud-storage-with-aws-libraries-go-lang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 01:08:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2015/google-cloud-storage-with-aws-libraries-go-lang/</guid><description>&lt;p> 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/overview">Google Cloud storage&lt;/a>
  it’s Google answer to [Amazon S3][1] service. As long one of them is very popular 😉 Second wasn’t so successful amongst developers due to quite complex processes around service. Amazon is super simple, and developer friendly – Google… well not so easy. So the questions – why you may consider using GS instead of well documented, and super easy S3. Not many people realise but Google Cloud Storage is 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="http://www.cloudberrylab.com/blog/amazon-s3-azure-and-google-cloud-prices-compare/">actually cheaper&lt;/a>
 . The other reason to use Google Storage is having different provider as a backup solution. Anyway – let’s show how easy is to use GS with existing S3 libraries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VPN server on EC2 instance</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/vpn-server-on-ec2-instance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 05:44:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/vpn-server-on-ec2-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The easiest way to setup VPN server on Amazon EC2 instance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apache 2.4, PHP 5.4 on EC2 instance</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/apache-2-4-php-5-4-on-ec2-instance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 04:04:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2014/apache-2-4-php-5-4-on-ec2-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>This tutorial just updated version of my 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/apache-php-config-boilerplate/" title="Amazon EC2 – Installing Apache and PHP boilerplate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">previous one&lt;/a>
 . This time we are going to install newer version of apache (httpd 2.4), PHP 5.4 but as a 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://wiki.apache.org/httpd/PHP-FPM">PHP-FPM&lt;/a>
 . Instructions are pretty simple. You can just copy and paste command to get working stack in less then 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you can learn from it? How to install Apache 2.4 and PHP 5.4, how to enable and APC, and how to install HTTPS on your server, with purchasing SSL certificate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free virtual machines with Internet Explorer</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/free-virtual-machines-with-internet-explorer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 05:22:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/free-virtual-machines-with-internet-explorer/</guid><description>BrowserStack is well known service which provides awesome tools to test your website against different browsers and operating systems. It’s very handy when it comes to professional QA testing.
Not everyone knows, that from that place you can also download virtual machines for free. On this page Virtual Machine you can pull multiple VM images with IE8 / IE 9 and different versions of windows.</description></item><item><title>Why AWS is better than Rackspace</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-aws-is-better-than-rackspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m huge fan of 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com">AWS&lt;/a>
 services. It just works – don’t need any kind of support, prices are really good. No issues whatsoever. But – of course my nature ask me to check out other options. For example 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com.au/">Rackspace&lt;/a>
 . So I registered account, filled out my business and credit details. Just to give a small background – got registered business since 2011 in Australia. I filled out my CC details, phone number and so on. Pretty standard process. I logged in, and start playing with their interface (pretty slow, but I shouldn’t complain yet). The best is about to come…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I don’t recommend mailgun…</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-i-dont-recommend-mailgun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 23:26:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/why-i-dont-recommend-mailgun/</guid><description>Couple months ago I listed services having API for sending and receiving emails . One of them was mailgun – I was using it for a while since… yesterday. My account was locked without any valid reason. Something related with SPAM:
http://documentation.mailgun.com/razor.html Reference: #rzr01.
Because I know exactly what emails are being sent using my accounts (I keep track of each email coming out from the system) I was really interested how it could happen.</description></item><item><title>How to install node.js on AWS AMI Linux instance</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-install-node-js-on-aws-ami-linux-instance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 00:25:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/how-to-install-node-js-on-aws-ami-linux-instance/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s even simpler than more tutorials are saying. After login to instance, just enable EPEL repository&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EC2 Instance and SWAP space</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/ec2-instance-and-swap-space/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 23:07:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/ec2-instance-and-swap-space/</guid><description>&lt;p>EC2 Instances on Amazon out of the box, does not contain any 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="http://www.linux.com/news/software/applications/8208-all-about-linux-swap-space">SWAP space&lt;/a>
 . So if you exhaust memory, machine probably stuck. It’s very good practice, to give them at least slow SWAP memory to save instant crashes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Process is quite simple. Let’s check how much free space we have:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amazon EC2 – Installing Apache and PHP boilerplate</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/apache-php-config-boilerplate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 05:22:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2013/apache-php-config-boilerplate/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this extremely simply tutorial I’m going to show, how you can deploy basic LAMP stack on EC2 instance. Instruction are pretty basic, without extra comments. You can just copy and paste command to get working stack in lest then 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you can learn from it? How to install Apache and PHP, how to enable and run XCache accelerator, and how to run HTTPS on your server, with purchasing SSL certificate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amazon AWS finally in Australia</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2012/amazon-aws-finally-in-australia/</guid><description>Finally we can enjoy power and speed of Amazon AWS services, in Australia but… so far we can’t get full experience, it’s only for two services – Amazon Route 53 and Amazon CloudFront . So… in simple words we can enjoy with 100% SLA DNS service and global CDN with edge location based on Sydney.</description></item><item><title>Google Storage for Developers vs Amazon S3</title><link>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-storage-for-developers-vs-amazon-s3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:35:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spidersoft.com.au/2011/google-storage-for-developers-vs-amazon-s3/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just got activation for 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/apis/storage/">Google Storage for Developers&lt;/a>
 . Service is similar to 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon S3&lt;/a>
 but it’s served by Google and it’s still in beta mode – that’s mean that you can’t just register and use, and you have limited warranty about quality and uptime.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>